<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Book-notes - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/categories/book-notes/</link><description>Book-notes - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/categories/book-notes/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Win Friends and Influence People - Dale Carnegie</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/how-to-influence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/how-to-influence/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4865.How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 6/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>To get what you want, talk about what they want.</li>
<li>Praise, let them feel valued Ask questions instead of giving direct orders. understand their view.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t criticize or complain.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<p>The book was a nice reminder to be less egoistic and care more about the other to get what we want. The advise can be shortly summarized, but the anecdotes are nice to let it sink in.</p>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p>Gereon</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<h3 id="how-to-convince">How to convince</h3>
<p>Don&rsquo;t criticize or complain.</p>
<p>Emphasize what they want and how they can achieve it. Don&rsquo;t mention what you want.</p>
<p>See it from the other&rsquo;s perspective. Don&rsquo;t tell them how they are wrong: &ldquo;Hey boys, I see you are having a good time. I loved building fire when little. I know you don&rsquo;t intend to do harm, but others see it. Would you bother go to another place next time and take care?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Be specific in praise. Introduce praise before criticism, but don&rsquo;t use the word &ldquo;but&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Ask questions instead of giving direct orders.</p>
<p>Make faults seem easy to correct.</p>
<p>Admit your own mistakes before criticizing the other person.</p>
<h3 id="affirmation-and-feeling-valued">Affirmation and feeling valued</h3>
<p>Be nice and smile. Ask for names. Ask again if you did not hear clearly. Ask to spell if difficult. People love to be greeted by name.</p>
<p>Find something admirable about the other, and compliment. People seek affirmation.</p>
<p>Let the other person feel that the idea is his or hers.</p>
<p>Praise to change of behavior. It gives people a reputation they want to maintain. We do our best when we feel valued and important.</p>
<p>Let the other person save face.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>The Almanack of Naval Ravikant - Eric Jorgenson</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/almanack-naval/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/almanack-naval/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/54898389-the-almanack-of-naval-ravikant" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>The book is available for <a href="https://www.navalmanack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">free</a>!</p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 7</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Only invest for the long-run: be it relationships, learning, money</li>
<li>Time is your most valuable resource. Spend money to buy time.</li>
<li>Be present in all that you do and meditate.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p>I became a fan of Naval through his <a href="/posts/2021-01-12-best-of-podcasts" rel="">episode</a> on the Knowledge project. Of course, I wanted to read this book after Eva Keiffenheim recommended it.</p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>I found it helpful to define life principles. Having them brings clearity, allows to prioritize and eases decision making. Does that sound good?</p>
<h2 id="-what-do-i-want-to-apply-to-my-life">👷🏼 What do I want to apply to my life?</h2>
<p>I want to spend more money to save time for what matters to me. I want a simple lifestyle, but outsourcing cooking, chores, bureaucracy is the luxury I aspire.
Commute is also a big time killer. The housing location is an important factor to me.</p>
<p>I want to defend my values more strongly, by speaking up and being less agreeable.
Accept to be disliked by people with different views.</p>
<p>I want to pay more attention that my environment (location, relationships, job) are nurturing my development and aligned with my principles.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<h3 id="go-deep-and-long-term">Go deep and long-term</h3>
<p>Invest deeply, when you find the right thing to do, when you find the right people (also applies to learning). Sticking with it for decades is really how you make the big returns in your relationships and in your money. Go all-in to benefit from compound interest.</p>
<p>Let go, once you are are not fully convinced. When you&rsquo;re dating, the instant you know this relationship is not going to be the one that leads to marriage, you should probably move on. When you&rsquo;re studying something and realize you are never going to use the information, drop it.</p>
<p>To make an original contribution, you have to be irrationally obsessed with something.</p>
<h2 id="spend-to-improve-your-time-spent">Spend to improve your time spent</h2>
<p>I hate wasting time. I&rsquo;m very famous for being rude at parties, events, dinners, where the moment I figure out it&rsquo;s a waste of my time, I leave immediately.</p>
<p>Value your time. It is all you have. It&rsquo;s more important than your money. It&rsquo;s more important than your friends.</p>
<p>Set and enforce an aspirational hourly pay rate. How much is my time worth? Live your aspirational lifestyle (or visualize) and see how much you need in a month (+ retirement). How much time do I want to reserve for other things? ^4135df</p>
<p>You may want to eat your healthy home cooked meals, but if you can outsource it, do that instead. It&rsquo;s one of the few luxuries I aspire!</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t get rich by spending your time to save money. You get rich by saving your time to make money.</p>
<p>If fixing a problem will save less than your hourly rate, ignore it. Doing something to not lose money (return broken speaker, argue with electrician&hellip;), might be more expensive. Opportunity cost! If outsourcing a task will cost less than your hourly rate, outsource it.</p>
<h2 id="priorities">Priorities</h2>
<p>The big decision in early life are: where you live, who you&rsquo;re with, and what you do. Spend time to decide and invest in getting options on these!</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re going to live in a city for ten years, if you&rsquo;re going to be in a job for five years, if you&rsquo;re in a relationship for a decade, you should be spending one to two years deciding these things.</p>
<h2 id="values">Values</h2>
<p>I think you just have to be very careful about doing things you are fundamentally not going to be proud of, because they will damage you.</p>
<p>The first time someone acts unacceptably, I will warn them. By the way, nobody changes. Then I just distance myself from them. I cut them out of my life.</p>
<p>The closer you want to get to me, the better your values have to be.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s possible to be honest and positive. Tell what you think! Charisma is the ability to project confidence and love at the same time.</p>
<p>If you can&rsquo;t decide, the answer is no.</p>
<p>For old problems like how to keep your body healthy, how to stay calm and peaceful, what kinds of value systems are good, how you raise a family, and those kinds of things, the older solutions are probably better.</p>
<p>Happiness is the absence of desire.</p>
<p>You can literally destroy your happiness if you spend all of your time living in delusions of the future.</p>
<p>I have lowered my identity. I have lowered the chattering of my mind. I don&rsquo;t care about things that don&rsquo;t really matter. I don&rsquo;t get involved in politics. I don&rsquo;t hang around unhappy people. I really value my time on this earth.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t beat yourself up saying: I need to do this and that. No, you don&rsquo;t need to do anything. All you should do is what you want to do.</p>
<p>Whenever we say we&rsquo;re going to try to do something or try to form a habit, we&rsquo;re wimping out. The reality is when our emotions want us to do something, we just do it. If you want to go approach a pretty girl, you just do it.</p>
<h2 id="career">Career</h2>
<p>For juniors, the single most important thing about a company is the alumni network you&rsquo;re going to build.</p>
<p>Trying to build business relationships well in advance of doing business is a complete waste of time.</p>
<p>Work intensly and then rest intensely.</p>
<p>CEOs are highly paid because of their leverage. Small differences in judgment and capability really get amplified.</p>
<h2 id="via-negativa">Via negativa</h2>
<p>Great ideas come when you are bored. Make time for it! Leave empty times in your calendar.</p>
<p>I do view a lot of my goals over the next few years of unconditioning previous learned responses or habituated responses. Subract, instead of always trying to add. Via negativa.</p>
<p>I think being successful is just about not making mistakes. It&rsquo;s not about having correct judgment. It&rsquo;s about avoiding incorrect judgments.</p>
<p>When it comes to medicine and nutrition, subtract before you add.</p>
<h2 id="accept">Accept</h2>
<p>Just accept how things are. You don&rsquo;t make any decisions. You don&rsquo;t judge anything. If I do that for ten or fifteen minutes while walking around, I end up in a very peaceful, grateful state. Choiceless Awareness works well for me.</p>
<p>As you watch your thoughts, you realize how many of them are fear-based. The moment you recognize a fear, without even trying it goes away. After a while, your mind quiets.</p>
<h3 id="life-philosophy">Life philosophy</h3>
<p>At the very least, I do not want my sense of self to continue to develop and strengthen as I get older. I want it to be weaker and more muted so I can be more in present everyday reality, accept nature and the world for what it</p>
<p>The less you want something, the less you&rsquo;re thinking about it, the more you&rsquo;re going to do it in a natural way. The more you&rsquo;re going to do it for yourself.</p>
<p>It doesn&rsquo;t matter what others think, it matters how you act to their behavior. So rather try to be your best self, while embracing (outspoken) feedback from others.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Crucial Conversations - Tools for Talking When Stakes Are High</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/crucial-conversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/crucial-conversations/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15014.Crucial_Conversations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 8/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>We can be honest and critical but also have a healthy dialogue, when approached correctly.</li>
<li>To step out of heated feelings, we need to trace back the path of action (storytelling!)</li>
<li>Always restore safety before opening a discussion.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<p>The book teaches pratical techniques to deal better with high stake conversations and includes many examples. It is easy to digest and often feels obvious, but taking it into practice needs repetition and reflection. I&rsquo;m listening to the book for the second time now. When mastered into practice this book can be worth gold, as the many letters from readers indicate.</p>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p>Audible suggestion</p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>I am sure everyone can benefit in their personal life. In business, especially people in managing positions will find it helpful.</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>I used to be very diplomatic and soft in conversations. Ofen, I would rather downplay my thoughts and opinions to avoid conflict or irritation. This of course does not lead to good outcomes. The book revealed to me that it&rsquo;s very possible to openly and honestly address touchy topics.</p>
<p>Many times discussions fail because, we are caught by our emotions. The concept of path to action makes clear how our strong feelings often stem from stories we make up from observations. We don&rsquo;t judge by facts but by stories. It takes attentive observation and thinking to step out of this vicious loop.</p>
<h2 id="-what-do-i-want-to-apply-to-my-life">👷🏼 What do I want to apply to my life?</h2>
<p>Observe my signals of how I react to piling up emotions in crucial conversations.
Only then can I step back and remind myself what I&rsquo;m really trying to achieve. Only then can I question my story and think of other reasonable interpretations of the facts.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<p>Forms of silence: masking, avoiding, withdrawing.<br>
People get silent when safety is lost. Safety is when you can say anything.<br>
Masking: underestimating, sugar coating: &ldquo;That&rsquo;s quite an unusual idea you came up with&rdquo;
Avoiding: change topics: &ldquo;What do you think of the dress?&hellip; I like that blue, it&rsquo;s my favorite color.&rdquo;
Withdrawing: exit conversation: &ldquo;Excuse me, I need to go and do x&rdquo;</p>
<p>Forms of violence: controlling, labeling, attacking.<br>
Controlling: cut others off, overstate, change topic. Hyperboles are used due to lacking facts<br>
Labeling: &ldquo;your ideas are Neanderthal.. Don&rsquo;t Listen, they are..&rdquo;
Attacking: belittle, say bad things about others</p>
<p>When we are verbally attacked, adrenaline kicks in and diverts blood flow from brain to body parts for flying. So, take a second and don&rsquo;t respond immediately to strong emotions.</p>
<p>We tend to stress small differences instead of looking for similarities. Try to agree and add. If you don&rsquo;t agree at all, compare the views, but don&rsquo;t disagree</p>
<h3 id="decision-making">Decision making</h3>
<p>See discussion as a way to collect views and ideas not as an approval to make decisions on others behalf.
Clear up how to make a decision. While everyone should add to the pool of meaning, not necessarily everyone is involved in the decision. Be clear on that.</p>
<ul>
<li>be specific in assigning responsibility: &ldquo;we&rdquo; means &ldquo;not me&rdquo;</li>
<li>define deadlines</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="path-of-action">Path of action</h3>
<p>observation -&gt; story -&gt; feelings -&gt; action</p>
<h3 id="dealing-with-difficult-situations">Dealing with difficult situations</h3>
<p>When people invent ever new excuses or a single instance seems ridiculous to bring up mention the pattern: Instead of don’t say this.. say don’t say things that might hurt your sisters feelings.
Instead of just fixing the Alarm clock, say sure if that helps that you are not late anymore.</p>
<p>On touchy topics. Mention difficulty to bring it up and show good intention.</p>
<p>Crucial conversations are not all or nothing. You cannot force the other to have dialogue, but by consistently signalling readiness for dialogue, you can eventually restore safety.</p>
<p>Touching can help restore safety among friends and family.</p>
<h3 id="0-reflect--prepare">0. Reflect + prepare</h3>
<p>Define your goal: I want a fair share of inheritance and keep a good relationship with my sister</p>
<p>Prepare the facts. Be specific in your critique. Instead of you &ldquo;You often do x when this happens&rdquo;, give an example!</p>
<p>Examine your role in the problem. We almost always also have a share in the problem. Try to see how a reasonable and rational human being could come to the others conclusion.</p>
<h3 id="1-establish-mutual-purpose">1. Establish mutual purpose</h3>
<p>Show why they would want to have a conversation. &ldquo;This is not easy, but I want to bring up a sensitive topic because it affects our relationship and that with others. I think it might help if you would know what others think.&rdquo;</p>
<h3 id="2-state-your-path">2. State your path</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Since mom needed care, I&rsquo;ve been taking care of her and covered her expenses. Her medication and therapy were a financial burden and I feel its fair that I get reimbursed for what I paid.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>give objective perception, then interpretation: make it tentative</li>
<li>ask for other view</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-detect-when-you-go-to-silence-or-violence">3. Detect when you go to silence or violence</h3>
<h3 id="4-restore-safety">4. Restore Safety</h3>
<p>trace their path of action</p>
<p>Use mirroring: &ldquo;You seem upset about my claim and feel that I&rsquo;m trying to rip you off&rdquo;; &ldquo;So you are feeling misjudged and belittled, is that what is going on&rdquo;?</p>
<p>Ask: &ldquo;Is this what&rsquo;s going on?&rdquo; &ldquo;How do you see it?&rdquo; &ldquo;What makes you think that you did more?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Use contrasting: &ldquo;I did not mean to hurt you. What I really wanted is to show you is&hellip;&rdquo;</p>
<p>Find similarities and agree: &ldquo;I totally agree that you were also taking efforts to visit mom and that these trips were not cheap. It&rsquo;s just that the costs I covered were even bigger&rdquo;</p>
<h3 id="5-getting-the-goal">5. Getting the goal</h3>
<p>Find common goals. People often pursue strategies: &ldquo;I want to stay here&rdquo;. But the higher goal is &ldquo;I want to be calm and not lose friends&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Make it easy for the other party to admit their fault: &ldquo;Hey, I&rsquo;m sure you are in a hurry and the queue is enormous. I also don&rsquo;t have much time and needed to come here 2 hours early&hellip; Do you agree that we should all be dealt fairly? Since most of us have rough schedules?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t coerce through power, show them the consequences of their behavior. There is often a connection between something we want to change, and some consequence they care about but are not aware of.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a Fuck - Mark Manson</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/giving-a-fuck/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/giving-a-fuck/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28257707-the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-f-ck" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 9/10</p>
<p>Additional source: <a href="https://sive.rs/book/NotFuck" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Sivers book notes</a></p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Don&rsquo;t crave for pleasures and an &ldquo;all-is-perfect&rdquo; life. Face reality and do your best. The good stuff will come as a by-product.</li>
<li>Closely inspect your values. Most roots of failure lie there. Find values that pose better problems</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t avoid problems, just find the ones you care about. Working on problems gives meaning and leads to happiness.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p>Sivers book list</p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s a self-help book, so those that like to ask themselves questions</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behaviour / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<p>I want to define myself simple and modest. According to Manson&rsquo;s law we avoid what threatens our identity, so I want to hold as few as possible and keep a low expectation of myself. My identity is fluid and I can change to become who I want to be, regardless of my past me.</p>
<h3 id="my-wrong-values">My wrong values</h3>
<p>The book made me question the root of my failures. I&rsquo;ve been wanting to establish a writing habit and yet I often procrastinate. I believe that it&rsquo;s related to my high expectations that I fear to fall behind. It&rsquo;s a wrong value, because it inhibits me from becoming a good writer. A better value is to see myself as an amateur who just wants to get better. A bad draft is something that can be improved upon! Nothing will remain nothing.</p>
<p>I sometimes defer programming because the task seems overwhelming and fear to feel uncomfortable about my skills. Honestly, I&rsquo;ve made big progress and when problems are properly broken up, I get to solve almost all of them. As a better value, I want to embrace difficulty and discovering my weaknesses because that&rsquo;s how to learn. If it were easy, I wouldn&rsquo;t be learning!</p>
<p>I still catch myself often backing down to talk to strangers on the street, particularly girls. I found that it&rsquo;s related to a social norm I formed while growing up in Germany. The norm is that it&rsquo;s not proper in public space, only desperate guys do so with inappropriate pick-up lines. And of course I am too noble to do that!
That&rsquo;s so wrong because I&rsquo;ve seen for myself how well received it can be.
In reality, I&rsquo;m just making up stupid excuses for my cowardness.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<p>Find what you want to give a fuck about, otherwise you will devote it to trivia.</p>
<p>Pleasure is the most artificial joy. Don&rsquo;t seek it; it&rsquo;s a by-product of good values.</p>
<p>Self improvement is about finding better values, choosing what to give a fuck about. With better fucks, come better problems, and with them you get a better life.</p>
<h3 id="no-pain-no-gain">No pain, no gain</h3>
<p>We suffer to learn; to improve our actions. Instead of trying to avoid problems, find the problems you are happy to solve.</p>
<p>Giving a fuck just means being willing to eat shit for what is important to you. It&rsquo;s not about being indifferent about everything.</p>
<p>Define your goals through the process and not by the outcome. Often we want things for their outcome, not for the process. Everyone wants to have nice relationships and have a trained body, but who enjoys to suffer for it? When we get to actually work towards the outcome, we see if we really want it.</p>
<p>Raising a child, will feel better than playing video games (=pleasure). Founding a company with friends is arduous, but looking back you will feel much more fullfiled than going to a bar every night.</p>
<p>When embracing a new value, accept that it will be painful. It will seem difficult. Accept that you never know what you are doing, until you do it. Just do it.</p>
<p>The desire to avoid rejection at all costs, to avoid confrontation and conflict, is a deep valueless, pleasure-driven, and self-absorbed life.</p>
<h3 id="be-humble">Be humble</h3>
<p>Media devotes it&rsquo;s attention to the extremes of the bell curve which distorts our perception of the norm. We seek to become extraordinary, failing to accept that we will most likely be average on most things.</p>
<p>People who are extraordinary believe they are mediocre which drives them to improve.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t seek the extreme but focus on the average experiences. These make up your life and matter the most.</p>
<h3 id="negative-emotions">Negative emotions</h3>
<p>If you feel crappy it’s because your brain is telling you that there’s a problem that’s unaddressed or unresolved.</p>
<p>Bad feelings mostly stem from values. Ask why you value this, and if the metric is accurate.</p>
<p>Define yourself through how you deal with negative happenings. You can&rsquo;t always prevent the event, but you are always responsible for the reaction!</p>
<p>Negative emotions are a biological signal to change. Positive emotions reward actions. Question if these tendencies are aligned with your values.</p>
<p>People overidentify with their emotions. “I was really mad; I couldn’t help it.”</p>
<h3 id="being-always-positive-can-be-negative">Being always positive can be negative</h3>
<p>Wanting positive experience is a negative experience; accepting negative experience is a positive experience.</p>
<p>A positive attitude doesn&rsquo;t make you good. It&rsquo;s possible to blow smoke and don&rsquo;t achieve anything (bullshiters).</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s wrong to always feel positive about whatever happens. It makes you dodge the problems, but overcoming problems is what gives your life meaning. A life without pain is not worthy and won&rsquo;t make you happy. No pain, no gain!</p>
<h3 id="personality">Personality</h3>
<p>Mansons law: the more something threatens your identity, the more you will avoid it.</p>
<p>Set low standards and beliefs of you. You are not special. This is the first step to get over the fear of failing to live up to your identity.</p>
<p>Having a loose (fluid) identity makes you less afraid to lose your identity.</p>
<h3 id="self-awareness">Self-awareness</h3>
<ol>
<li>layer: Perceive your emotions</li>
<li>layer: Understand why we feel certain emotions? :
Why do you feel angry? Is it because you failed to achieve some goal?<br>
Why do you feel lethargic and uninspired? Is it because you don’t think you’re good enough?</li>
<li>layer: Define personal values.
Why do I consider this to be success/failure?<br>
How am I choosing to measure myself?<br>
By what standard am I judging myself and everyone around me?</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="values">Values</h3>
<p>The 5 golden values:</p>
<ol>
<li>Take responsibility</li>
<li>Accept uncertainty, acknowledge ignorance, doubt your beliefs.</li>
<li>Discover your flaws and learn from failures</li>
<li>Give and take rejections. Say no to what you don&rsquo;t want in your life and accept to hear a no.</li>
<li>Contemplate your own mortality</li>
</ol>
<p>Good (internal) values are honesty, stand up for oneself and others, modesty, curiosity, charity.</p>
<p>Be open to change your values to find new happiness.</p>
<p>Does changing your values pose a better problem? E.g.: Continue to reject the husband of the sister and cause trouble, vs respect her decision and acknowledge own insecurity to accept her marriage.</p>
<p>Seeing where your values are wrong, brings you closer to a problem&rsquo;s solution.</p>
<p>When embracing a new value, accept that it will be painful. It will seem difficult. Accept that you never know what you are doing, until you do it. Just do it. Be it talking to girls, deciding to drop a major you hate..</p>
<p>Defining values means rejecting other options.</p>
<p>Be honest and straight to say no to things that conflict with your values or priorities. It&rsquo;s helpful for your relationships in that it fosters trust.</p>
<h3 id="relationships">Relationships</h3>
<p>In a healthy relationship, each takes responsibility for their own problems. Acts of love are unconditional without any kind of guilt involved. Ask yourself, “If I refused, how would the relationship change?”</p>
<p>Their love is based on mutual respect and acknowledging the others weaknesses and supporting them to solve their struggles.</p>
<p>Healthy lovers don&rsquo;t get upset about an argument or action, because they don&rsquo;t expect their partner to solve their problems.</p>
<p>If someone cheats in a relationship, it&rsquo;s because they give higher value to something like: power of others, validation through sex, giving into impulses.</p>
<h3 id="commit">Commit</h3>
<p>Explore the world and experience in breadth when young. Then settle for a choice and reject the other options. We feel happier once settling for one option, because we don&rsquo;t worry about the other options anymore. Also it allows us to have deeper experiences. Knowing a partner for a decade, mastering a craftsmanship..</p>
<p>We are defined by what we choose to reject.</p>
<p>When stuck on a problem, don’t think too much about it; just start working on it. It&rsquo;s okay to not know what you&rsquo;re doing, but acting will make you eventually discover the right ideas.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>How To Live - Derek Sivers</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/how-to-live/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/how-to-live/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58188742-how-to-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 9/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>There is no one answer on how to live well.</li>
<li>Our attittude and perspectives on what feels right change within the different life phases.</li>
<li>All the conflicting ideas have in common that they bring intention to how we live.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<p>It was maybe the most thought provoking book I&rsquo;ve read this year. I had several epiphanies; moments where I got excited: &ldquo;Yees, that&rsquo;s it to the point&hellip; Wow, I never thought about it like this..&rdquo;. There were also many ideas that did not attract me, but I still found it interesting to consider them. I also recognized many ideas and found connections to other books, which gave the pleasant feeling that I took something from the other readings.</p>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p>I was a Sivers fan before</p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>The book is a compilation of ideas on how to live a good life. It&rsquo;s thought-provoking has many conflicting ideas that each have their appeal. It takes you on self exploration to find which attitudes and life principles attract you. Sivers writing is very concise, making it a quick-read. You will most likely spend much more time thinking than reading. Highly recommend!</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behaviour / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<p>Personalities are fluid. I don&rsquo;t need to stick to past traits just because that&rsquo;s how people know me. The impediment for change is just in my head. I can be who I want to be and what feels best right now.</p>
<p>The commitment to have a routine got reinforced. I want to reserve the morning for learning, work during the day, do exercise in the afternoon, and journal in the evening.</p>
<p>I want to be more social. I want to talk to more people, invite people for a meal. I want to build a deeper connection with my family. I got reminded again that building deep friendships require effort, but that it is worth investing.
I noticed how some people make me feel more comfortable being myself. They are open and revealing about themselves.</p>
<p>I want to commit more and stop trying to find something better. I often find myself indecisive about trivia. I realize that it only matters how you feel about a choice and not whether it is objectively the best.
This also applies to love. I&rsquo;ve been idealizing it too much, always finding something that is not optimal or &ldquo;missing&rdquo;.
I think happiness in a relationship is more about commiting to it. A partner does not need to connect on all levels (there are other significant others). It&rsquo;s really about finding someone full of kindness who is committed to putting you in the center of their life. Maybe the only additional requirement is a shared core value set.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<p><em>My notes are quotes from the book, since it is difficult to put it even more concise..</em></p>
<h3 id="be-independent">Be independent</h3>
<p>Never agree with anything the same day you hear it, because some ideas are persuasively hypnotic. Wait a few days to decide what you really think.</p>
<p>Friends are great at the right distance. Just like you can’t read something if it’s pushed up against your face, or too far away, you should keep your friends at arm’s length — close but not too close.</p>
<p>Have more than one romantic partner, or none. To avoid emotional dependence, never have just one. Don’t worry about being lonely. Nothing is more lonely than being with the wrong person.</p>
<p>You can’t be free without self-mastery. Your past indulgences and habits might be addictions. Quit a harmless habit for a month, just to prove you can.</p>
<p>When you say you want more freedom from the world, you may just need freedom from your past self.</p>
<p>Be a perpetual traveler, living out of a suitcase. Give away everything you haven’t used in a week. Ownership binds you to the past. Don’t get invested in any one thing.</p>
<p>Own your own business with many small customers to avoid depending on any big client. Offer products, not a personal service, so your business can run without you. Create many sources of income like this.</p>
<p>Don’t sign contracts. Be willing to walk away from anything.</p>
<p>You can appreciate everything from a healthy distance. You can appreciate your country from abroad, once it’s not your only option. You can appreciate family, once they’re not forced upon you.</p>
<h3 id="commit">Commit</h3>
<p>If you’ve ever been confused or distracted, with too many options… If you don’t finish what you start… If you’re not with a person you love… … then you’ve felt the problem. The problem is a lack of commitment.</p>
<p>You can stop seeking the best option. Pick one and irreversibly commit.<br>
You make it the best through your commitment to it.</p>
<p>When a decision is irreversible, you feel better about it. When you’re stuck with something, you find what’s good about it. When you can’t change your situation, you change your attitude towards it. So remove the option to change your mind.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t overthink trivial choice like which desert or bread to buy. Just decide on one and go for it.</p>
<p>Let go of every unnecessary obligation.</p>
<p>Choose your home. Stay there for good. Get to know everything about it. Hire a local expert and learn about areas you haven’t explored.</p>
<p>Find a community of like-minded people. Don’t waste your energy fighting norms.</p>
<p>The pursuit of mastery helps you think long-term. It keeps your eyes on the horizon. You resist the temptation of what you want now. You remember the importance of what you want most. You spend time intentionally. Every month has a milestone. Every day has a goal. The most rewarding things in life take years. Only bad things happen quickly.</p>
<p>Passion come from “pati”, meaning “to suffer or endure”. To be passionate about something is to be willing to suffer for it — to endure the pain it’ll bring.</p>
<p>You’re defined by what you do repeatedly. Your habits create your character.</p>
<p>You need ritual, not inspiration. Every day, no matter what, you must practice. It&rsquo;s the highest priority. A routine triggers inspiration because your mind and body learn that ideas emerge at that time.</p>
<h3 id="relationships">Relationships</h3>
<p>Trust helps your happiness more than income or health. Invite your neighbors over for a meal. Make friends. Make the effort. Borrow and lend. Trust and show you can be trusted. Let them know they can lean on you because you’re here to stay. They’ll reciprocate.</p>
<p>The more social ties we have, the happier we are. The bond of friendship is one of the deepest joys in life. Notice those words: ties, bond. These are words of commitment. We say we want freedom, in theory. But we actually prefer this warm embrace.</p>
<p>If you want a successful network of connections, what matters is not how many people you know but how many different kinds of people you know.</p>
<p>After age twenty, you need deliberate effort to make new friends. Friends are made, not found.</p>
<p>Humor means using your mind beyond necessity, beyond reality, for both noticing and imagining. It shows you quickly looked at something from many angles, found the one that amused you the most, and considerately expressed it to someone else.</p>
<p>Small talk is just a way of matching the other person’s tone and mood. It helps them be comfortable with you.</p>
<p>Whenever you’re thinking something nice about someone, tell them. A sincere compliment can put a lot of fuel in someone’s tank. People don’t hear enough compliments.</p>
<p>Ideally, when with others, be the same person you’d be when alone.<br>
Keep communicating instead of shutting down. We think walls protect us from enemies, but walls are what create enemies in the first place.</p>
<p>Don’t text when you should talk. Avoid habitual comebacks and clichés. Admit what you’re really feeling, even when it’s uncomfortable.</p>
<p>The more you really connect with people, the more you learn about yourself: what excites you, what drains you, what attracts you, and what intimidates you.</p>
<p>Notice who makes you feel more connected with yourself — more open and more honest.</p>
<h3 id="love">Love</h3>
<p>Not love, the feeling, but love the active verb. It’s not something that happens to you. It’s something you do. You choose to love something or someone.</p>
<p>If you have feelings for someone, and you don’t let that person know, you’re lying with your silence. Be direct. It saves so much trouble and regret.</p>
<p>Instant obsessive love is a bad sign that you’re thinking of someone as the solution. Projecting perfection onto someone is not love. You say “I love you” but really mean “I love this”.</p>
<p>Love brings the pain of attachment. If you avoid pain, you avoid what you really want.</p>
<p>Falling in love is easy. Staying in love is harder. Enthusiasm is common. Endurance is rare.</p>
<p>Marry someone full of kindness who is committed to putting you in the center of their life. Marry someone you don’t want to change, who doesn’t want to change you. Someone that doesn’t punish you for mistakes. Someone who sees you as your highest potential. Commit completely.</p>
<p>Marriage is for getting through the times when you’re not in love. Expect things to get bad. Your mutual commitment gives you the security to weather the storms, knowing they won’t destroy the relationship. Be loving even when you’re not feeling loving. Commitment gives you peace of mind. When you commit to one thing, and let go of the rest, you feel free. Once you decide something, never change your mind. It’s so much easier to decide just once. Commitment gives you integrity and social bonds</p>
<h3 id="exploration">Exploration</h3>
<p>Maximize your inputs. See all the places. Eat all the food. Hear all the music. Meet all the people. Kiss all the beauties. Be insatiable.</p>
<p>Be systematic. Follow guides. “Top Places You Must Visit” “Greatest Movies of All Time” “Best Restaurants in Town” Go through them all. That’s the optimized way to experience the most, without repetition.</p>
<p>Experience pain, anger, sorrow, and more. Don’t judge them as bad. Notice how they really feel.</p>
<p>Practice seduction. Be with a different person every night. Every lover is different.</p>
<p>Practice feeling emotions intentionally, instead of using actions to create them. You don’t need marriage to feel security. Marriage doesn’t make you secure.</p>
<p>Move to a quiet place with lots of nature and no ambition. Doing nothing is normal there. Walk and appreciate nature for hours a day. Your life and mind will be tranquil and serene. Peace is the absence of turmoil. You won’t need the media, the internet, or a phone. Your cost of living will be hardly more than local eggs and vegetables</p>
<p>You can’t see your own culture while you’re inside of it.</p>
<p>Go make memories. Experience the unusual. Replace your routines. Live in different places.</p>
<p>Journal every day. Write down your activities, thoughts, and feelings for future reference.</p>
<p>Turn your experiences into stories. A story is the remains of an experience. Make your stories entertaining, so people like to hear them.</p>
<p>When talking with people, ask deep open-ended questions — like “What’s your biggest regret?” — that will lead to unexpected stories.</p>
<p>Do a ten-day silent meditation.</p>
<p>Visit Singapore, Jakarta, Addis Ababa, Lagos, Mumbai, Ho Chi Minh City, and Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Move to South Korea, and keep an apartment in Songdo, Incheon. South Korean culture places the highest value on what’s new. Work as a futurist
Watch the greatest movies of all time. Read the classics. Listen to the legends. These things have lasted because they work so well. Time is the best filter.</p>
<p>If you’re not embarrassed by what you thought last year, you need to learn more and faster.</p>
<p>When you’re really learning, you’ll feel stupid and vulnerable.</p>
<p>Talk with people you usually avoid.</p>
<p>Get out of your room and try out a new skill in the real world. Go to the physical place where it’s happening, and put your ass on the line with something to lose. A vivid, visceral feeling of danger will teach you better than words.</p>
<p>Great public speaking comes from great private thinking.</p>
<p>Go light-weight camping for a week.</p>
<p>When something bad happens, ask, “What’s great about this?” Instead of changing the world, just change your reactions.</p>
<p>Visit your favorite places. Listen to your favorite music. Taste your favorite food. Touch your favorite people. This might be the last time you do all these things, so appreciate each moment fully.</p>
<p>Spend your social time meeting new people. You’re not the same person you were last year or even last week. Old friends and family see you as you used to be, and unintentionally discourage your growth.</p>
<h3 id="decision-making">Decision making</h3>
<p>Let &ldquo;No&rdquo; be the default answer. People mistakenly say yes to work, people, and places they don’t like, then need to escape to get away from their mistakes. People make bad decisions because they felt they had to decide. It would have been wiser to do nothing.</p>
<p>When a problem is bothering you, it feels like you need to do something about it. Instead, identify what belief is really the source of your trouble. Replace that belief with one that doesn’t bother you.</p>
<p>When someone asks you to decide, just refuse. The longer you go without deciding, the more information is revealed. Eventually, the choice is obvious and made without an agonizing decision.</p>
<p>Just because somebody asked you a question doesn’t mean you have to answer it. Dramatic people are fueled by reactions. When you stop reacting, they go away.</p>
<p>If an action feels necessary, and you can’t let it go, just write it down for later. Everything seems more important while you’re thinking of it. Later, you’ll realize it’s not.
But if it still feels necessary, adjust your time frame. A year from now, will it be important? Ten years from now? Zoom out as far as you need to make it unimportant.</p>
<p>Don’t convince yourself your home is an asset. Your home is an expense, not an investment, because it doesn’t put money in your pocket each month.</p>
<p>Only spend money on things that do long-term good, like education. In other words, never spend, only invest. The earlier you start, the better, since time is the multiplier.</p>
<h3 id="be-uncomfortable">Be uncomfortable</h3>
<p>Choose pain in small doses to build your resistance to it. Set a daily challenge to feel uncomfortable.</p>
<p>Whatever scares you, go do it. Then it won’t scare you anymore.</p>
<p>When you make a big mistake and want to learn its lesson, deliberately amplify the pain, the deep regret, and the consequences.</p>
<p>Everything good comes from some kind of pain. Muscle fatigue makes you healthy and strong. The pain of practice leads to mastery. Difficult conversations save your relationships.</p>
<p>Avoid pain, and you avoid improvement. Avoid embarrassment, and you avoid success. Avoid risk, and you avoid reward.</p>
<p>Socially, try to get rejected. Learn about “rejection therapy”. Make audacious requests that you think will be denied. This removes the pain of rejection. And you’ll be surprised how often they say yes.</p>
<p>Be absolutely honest with everyone. Stop lying, completely. You lie when you’re afraid. You lie to avoid consequences. Always say the truth. Take the painful consequences.</p>
<p>Indulging is common. Refraining is rare.</p>
<p>Comfort reduces your future happiness. You get upset that your meal doesn’t come as ordered, or angry at your phone for having an imperfect connection. You lose appreciation. You forget the perspective of how bad things could be.</p>
<p>Practice being uncomfortable, even in small ways. Take the stairs instead of the elevator. Skip eating for a day, or sugar for a month.</p>
<p>Shallow happy is having a donut. Deep happy is having a fit body. Shallow happy is what you want now. Deep happy is what you want most. Shallow happy serves the present. Deep happy serves the future. Shallow happy is trying to conquer the world. Deep happy is conquering yourself. Shallow happy is pursuing pleasure. Deep happy is pursuing fulfillment.</p>
<h3 id="be-present">Be present</h3>
<p>Live today and forget about the future. If you want to do something, do it now. If you don’t want to do it now, then you don’t want to do it at all, so let it go.</p>
<p>Focus on whatever fascinates you now. When you’re happy, you think better. You’re more open to possibilities and connecting ideas. You learn better and are more creative. So forget the future and past.</p>
<p>People with severe amnesia are surprisingly happy. They can’t remember the past, and they don’t try to predict the future since they have no trajectory. They have only the present moment, so they enjoy it without burden. Follow their example. Forget the past and future.</p>
<p>Never make plans. When someone asks, just say you can’t know until that day.</p>
<h3 id="self-control">Self-control</h3>
<p>Following your emotions is not freedom. Being free from following emotions is freedom.</p>
<p>Random stuff happens. All you can control is your response. Every day, you’ll practice how to react to chaos: with dignity, poise, and grace.</p>
<p>An undisciplined moment seems harmless, but they add up to disaster. Without discipline, the tiny things in life will be your downfall.</p>
<p>Your self-control is highest in the morning and diminishes during the day, so review your book’s rules every afternoon.</p>
<p>Ignore everything new. Let the test of time filter everything. Value only what has endured</p>
<p>Ignore all marketing and advertising. Nobody is pushing what really matters. Friendships, nature, family, learning, community. The best things in life aren’t things.</p>
<p>Expecting life to be wonderful is disappointing. Expecting life to be disappointing is wonderful.</p>
<p>Rules may keep you from some stupendous heights, but they will always keep you from falling too low.</p>
<p>Schedule everything to ensure balance of your time and effort. Scheduling prevents procrastination, distraction, and obsession. A schedule makes you act according to the goals of your highest self, not your passing mood.</p>
<h3 id="create">Create</h3>
<p>Boring industries have little competition, since most people are seeking status in glamorous new fields. Find an old industry and solve an old problem in a new way.</p>
<p>Avoid difficult business problems. Your time is more profitably spent doing what comes easily to you.</p>
<p>It’s better to create something bad than nothing at all. You can improve something bad. You can’t improve nothing.</p>
<p>Embrace what’s weird about you, and use it to create.</p>
<p>Separate creation and release. When you’ve finished a work, wait a while before you release it to the world. By then, you’re on to something new. The public comments won’t affect you, since they will be about your past work.</p>
<p>Share your stories from all your mistakes for the benefit of the world.</p>
<p>Every time you hear a song, watch a show, or read an idea, think of how you’d change it or combine it with something else. Keep your tools handy to rearrange, remix, and edit what you encounter. Then share your alterations.</p>
<h3 id="via-negativa">Via negativa</h3>
<p>Most of eating healthy is just avoiding bad food.</p>
<p>To have good people in your life, just cut out the bad ones.</p>
<p>What do you want out of life? That’s hard to answer. What don’t you want? That’s easy. More than anything, we want a lack of negatives. A life with no pain, no injury, no regrets, and no disaster is a good life. It’s easy to find joy in everyday things, if you can just avoid the bad.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Deal!: Du gibst mir, was ich will - Jack Nasher</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/deal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/deal/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17737312-deal?from_search=true&amp;from_srp=true&amp;qid=yJgtOjZSuy&amp;rank=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 8/10</p>
<p>This book is only available in German, but my notes are in English :)</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Negotiation is about getting the best deal for both, it is not about finding a compromise.</li>
<li>Finding a good deal is about exploring all the options, it is not just about the price.</li>
<li>Negotiation is about psychology. Knowing the tiny tricks can protect you against them and give you an edge.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<p>This is my second book on negotiation, after having read <a href="/books/never-split-the-difference/" rel="">Never Split the Difference</a>. Interestingly, both share the same core message, that compromises should be avoided. In most cases it is possible that both parties get what is important to them. I feel that this book was more practical, since it provides advice on making better deals when buying a car, negotiating a salary, how to get the most out of long waiting times etc. The book is packed with tips and it did not get lengthy at any point.</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behaviour / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<p>Negotiation is an art and has many more dimensions than just the price. It revealed to me that being prepared with many variations of offers is a good way to find a deal that suits both.</p>
<p>I noticed that I lost lots of potential in the past by easily giving away things that are not very important to me, instead of using them as a leverage.</p>
<p>Moreover, I want to try out how accompanying a complaint with a satisfying solution is more effective.</p>
<p>I want to question my discontent more. It&rsquo;s probably not the action, but my interpretation that bugs me. To clear it up, I first state the facts to the other and then how I feel about it. I then ask about how they see it. This avoids attacking the other and indicates that I am not opinionated.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<h3 id="always-ask">Always ask</h3>
<p>Make the start to reveal information but in tiny bits and wait for the reaction of the other. Ask, don&rsquo;t talk, to get more information. Paraphrasing is effective to come to the same understanding.</p>
<p>When asking a friend, don&rsquo;t reveal your opinion before to get a more neutral view.</p>
<p>Ask questions, you will be surprised how willing people are to share information. Who can decide to negotiate? What offer do I get when I buy this as well?</p>
<p>Ask the big stuff early. People are more willing to give information before negotiation. Same for dating: question about previous partners during affair is much more likely to be successful. This also allows you to decide early whether to continue.</p>
<h3 id="choosing-a-communication-channel">Choosing a communication channel</h3>
<p>After phone calls, send the agreements per email to avoid &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve never said this&rdquo;.</p>
<p>We act very different on mail, where we don&rsquo;t need to face the other. People are often more shameless, so avoid it whenever possible.</p>
<p>Mail is better to avoid unwanted information leakage, and you don&rsquo;t risk to be persuaded because you feel bad! However, it&rsquo;s also much more likely to get a no on mail. So choose your communication channel depending on whether you want to communicate a no, or get a yes.</p>
<h3 id="winning-your-partner">Winning your partner</h3>
<p>Find similarities with the partner (even trivial and irrelevant ones).</p>
<p>Show weakness to make the other talk.</p>
<p>Find out what that person is good at. When he talks about it, your appreciation of him will increase. When you appreciate the power of the other, you won&rsquo;t try to take hold of it. Avoid that people with limited power, like officials, cling to their power.</p>
<p>Avoid disagreeing about negative points(e.g. you are expensive), but instead agree and provide a reason for it: Yes, and surely you value quality and service.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t attribute excuses to external factors, instead take the responsibility: I should have taken an earlier subway. This makes you more credible.</p>
<p>If it&rsquo;s not the action you feel sorry for, express sorry for the feeling you caused the other.</p>
<p>Build a bridge to make it easy for the other to change the behavior while maintaining his face: The no smoking sign is barely visible, but could you please go outside?</p>
<p>Make the other look like a winner. After closing a deal, tell the other how he made you pay more than you wanted..</p>
<h3 id="be-prepared">Be prepared</h3>
<p>No preparation, prepares a sure loss. Expect the preparation to take much longer than the negotiation itself.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t negotiate when you are not prepared and it doesn&rsquo;t have your full attention (e.g. outside, driving).</p>
<p>Be clear which information is relevant before the negotiation. Questions are the key to get them!</p>
<p>Enter a negotiation with a clear goal and knowing your best fallback option. Don&rsquo;t be as vague as trying to haggle as much as possible!</p>
<p>Negotiate with your favorite option last, when you had the chance to negotiate a proper fallback option.</p>
<p>Never lament. Instead make an offer to mitigate: &ldquo;I made a reservation and still need to wait a lot, therefore we go to the bar now, and I hope you invite us apéritifs while we are waiting&rdquo;. &ldquo;I can do the work for two, but then I want more money&rdquo;: Concession + Claim. Think of something concrete you would enjoy, instead of hoping that the other party offers something.</p>
<h3 id="finding-the-best-for-both">Finding the best for both</h3>
<p>We tend to believe that our interests are incompatibles. Both might want to close the window, but one person wants fresh air, and the other sitting next to the window feels its drafty.</p>
<p>Find what the other values. When both partners get a job offer in different cities, find out what it means for each other and how it might be compensated with something of higher value.</p>
<p>A compromise is not win win, but lose lose. Most likely there is a way to find a solution where no one needs to give up on what they value.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t focus too much on the price. There are many more non monetary values which might be of high value for you and cheap for the other. E.g hotel reservation: breakfast and spa is cheap for them, but very nice for you.</p>
<p>Try to get different offers to see how much the other values each component. Maybe you find a better match!</p>
<h3 id="the-role-of-psychology">The role of psychology</h3>
<p>Bringing a higher power into the negotiation, makes you more powerful. You might even invent it: I like it, but my wife says it&rsquo;s not worth more than x.. I need to consult with my manager.. Even the president does it, referring to the power of the senate.. It wins empathy that you are not the one making strong claims.</p>
<p>To avoid the partner from applying the trick of higher power delegation, ask early if there is a higher power: If that&rsquo;s the perfect house, could you make a decision today? Try to negotiate asap with the person in charge.</p>
<p>Scarcity makes things more attractive: The bus in Ghana always has only one seat left until the next actor gives up a place. Same for &ldquo;last offer&rdquo;. Scrutinize if the scarcity is real.</p>
<p>Never indicate a selling price as negotiable. This shows that you don&rsquo;t even think it&rsquo;s worth this price.</p>
<p>Build up a connection before talking about business. When your friendliness clashes with your extreme business goals, the other experiences cognitive dissonance, which they try to harmonize (similar to Stockholm syndrome).</p>
<p>Consistency principle: explore principles or the slogan of the other and use them to make claims: The flyer guarantees freshness, it doesn&rsquo;t mention any exclusion close to final hour.</p>
<p>When the police stops you, keep them from writing something down through questions and explanations. As soon as he writes it down, he will file the claim due to consistency (show no weakness).</p>
<p>Deadlines are often made up to push us to a deal.</p>
<p>The phony trick: when wanting to buy something, let people you know make very low offers and then make a slightly higher bet. Your low offer will appear high compared to the others.</p>
<p>Be wary of the good-guy bad-guy trick. The good guy tries to win your empathy by protecting you from the outrageous claims from the bad guy. If detected, mention it: &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve never seen such a good cop bad cop play&rdquo;..</p>
<p>Sound reasonable by bringing objective measures in to play. Before making the other aware of the consequences, ask them if they accept the criteria: &ldquo;Do you find it reasonable to compare prices to be fair?&rdquo;.</p>
<p>People prefer distributed wins (finding 2x 10 Euros vs 1x 20 Euros), but losing at once. Chunk advantages and perks to make them seem more.</p>
<p>Humans have a strong sense of fairness and even reject deals that are beneficial for them.</p>
<p>The absolute price limit can be detected by ever decreasing concessions.</p>
<p>Framing: Put arguments that correspond to the others view. If your boss wants to hire the best, argue how an assistant would give more time to focus on the core work. If he wants to save money, argue how it would stop the expensive work force from spending time doing paper work and copying.</p>
<p>Overcommitment phenomenon: After a big time investment, we are eager for closing a deal. Don&rsquo;t consider sunken cost, but always consider if the deal makes sense. Be wary of low balling: negatives are presented very late. On the other hand, you can use it to negotiate a better deal. Ask the other GRADUALLY for documents, information.. It&rsquo;s easy to say no in the beginning, so take it slowly. At the end of a long negotiation, you can ask for an upgrade, as if it were self evident. &ldquo;the gas tank will be filled right?&rdquo; after trying 10 different suits, ask &ldquo;which tie is included?&rdquo;</p>
<h3 id="the-first-offer-and-haggling">The first offer and haggling</h3>
<p>Be the first to make an offer for anchoring, unless you don&rsquo;t know anything.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t take absurd offers from the other party seriously / ignore them. Shrug together - body language seems more credible than words. Avoid that their offer becomes the anchor.</p>
<p>Set the anchor as a starting point for discussions. Signal willingness to negotiate: Through a rough estimate, I think it&rsquo;s worth&hellip; but maybe I missed something.. Last year the bonus was such, but I understand if it could not be that much this year.. My colleague earns that much, but I see that you might not be able to pay as much.. I think the car is worth its price, but our budget is only such..</p>
<p>Let them make the middle deal offer. &ldquo;There is not a lot missing between us, let&rsquo;s come to terms&rdquo;.. When they suggest it, you have still room to negotiate further.. I need to discuss it.. Now we are so close, how about meeting in the middle and close it..</p>
<p>The best time to haggle is after having a concrete offer from the partner and before accepting it. Before that, they might still decide for another option and after accepting it is too late.</p>
<h3 id="never-give-without-taking">Never give without taking</h3>
<p>Never make concessions easily, even if they don&rsquo;t cost you anything. Play them as sacrifice on your side to claim something.</p>
<p>Make concessions conditional; When you want/do that, then I want/do that. This way you make the other think what he has to offer, before he makes a claim.</p>
<p>If you make a high claim and then easily make concessions, you give the impression that you were trying to rip off.</p>
<p>The positive effect of concessions diminishes quickly, so ask for something in return immediately.</p>
<p>Agree on various unimportant points, to ask for something that is important to you.</p>
<p>When the other reveals a limitation / restriction, pretend that you are disappointed and ask for something in return: &ldquo;If it&rsquo;s like that, then we get a free breakfast at least?&rdquo;</p>
<p>When asking for a favor, have something in return to offer: When you stop throwing condoms in my garden, then you can always ring at my door when you need help or a warm coffee.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t be tricked by favors. We feel that favors need to be returned. If someone gives something for free, try to be prepared to have something in return to offer.</p>
<h3 id="dealing-with-heated-discussions">Dealing with heated discussions</h3>
<p>When a conversation heats up, take a pause to let the brain get control again. Or try to do something funny, e.g. put a rubber chicken on the table :D</p>
<p>To be vexed about someone else is to punish yourself for someone else&rsquo;s mistake</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t respond to attacks with counter attacks. Instead agree with the others anger: You are right, I feel the same.. This steals the others thunder.</p>
<p>When feeling annoyed about being in a Hotline for a while and not getting help, remind yourself that the goal is to solve the problem, not to show off your ego or piss the person off.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the explanation and not the action that vexes us. When the wife puts away the cereal bowl, you feel annoyed because you think she won&rsquo;t let you in peace. But she might do it to please you. Ask yourself or better the other if your explanation is wrong.</p>
<p>When complaining, first mention the facts and then explain how you feel about it. Instead of &ldquo;you are mean&rdquo; say: &ldquo;The last times it was like that.., I feel that&hellip;&rdquo;. Finally ask for the others opinion: Am I right? This indicates that you don&rsquo;t insist on your opinion.</p>
<h3 id="dealing-with-and-applying-threats">Dealing with and applying threats</h3>
<p>Keep threats only about your interests: If I don&rsquo;t get a table now, then my guests will take it very badly.. I have a family now and need more money to provide for them. I&rsquo;d like to continue working for you company, but what can we do?</p>
<p>Conflict resolution without threats: What would you do if you are constantly late?</p>
<p>Ignore threats and change the topic. Often it&rsquo;s an extremely emotional response and ignoring it, allows the other to maintain his face.</p>
<p>If the others threat is unavoidable, agree with their intent. Yes, we will try to find the best price.. Delegate power.. I&rsquo;d like to give you better offer, but this is not in my power.</p>
<p>If you show that you are willing to leave the negotiation it strengthens your perceived power and also tests the other party. How important is a deal to him? If so, there is still room for negotiation.</p>
<h3 id="put-agreements-on-paper">Put agreements on paper</h3>
<p>Document negotiation results on paper. Send an email afterwards with the protocol. If you write it, you have the power to emphasize the points you want.. Add a phrase like: If you don&rsquo;t disagree within a week, I assume that you agree to the conditions.</p>
<p>Always include contract punishments. They are not a sign of distrust, but a general procedure (my boss insists..).</p>
<p>Be open for renegotiation of a contract. Both might realize inconvenient points. If the other refuses to renegotiate, abuse claims of the contract.. Call support and ask for technician until they want to terminate your contract.</p>
<h3 id="a-few-more-tricks">A few more tricks</h3>
<p>Start on the lower end of the hierarchy. After a no, you can try at the next instance.. You only need one yes. Same goes for Hotlines: just call 2 if one tells you it&rsquo;s impossible.</p>
<p>Persistence is key. Don&rsquo;t give up after one no. But don&rsquo;t drive it to the extreme. Negotiations are not only about maximizing the outcome, but also about minimizing the input.</p>
<p>See most negotiations as a game. Will you remember it in 10 years? The playful attitude keeps you less emotional and gives the other less power, because you could always leave the negotiation.</p>
<p>We often mistake that what we know and perceive, is also what the other feels: Only few people can detect songs that the other knocks on the table. The knocker cannot believe how the other cannot hear it. This also applies to partners who know each other for years.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s helpful to assume the position of the other to understand the situation better. E.g: examine the position of the accused when you defend your client. We tend to be overconfident about our own position, and the role reversal reveals our weaknesses.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder - Nassim Nicholas Taleb</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/antifragile/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/antifragile/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13530973-antifragile" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 8/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>We can do well in a complex world we don&rsquo;t understand</li>
<li>Embrace to live in an unpredictable world and prepare for it by avoiding extreme harm.</li>
<li>Our world is non-linear: Many of our options might be useless, but one success can pay it all off.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<p>A good friend of mine read all of his books and liked them a lot, so I decided to choose one of the book series to see for myself. I chose Antifragility because many said that it is the most comprehensive - summarizing a lot of the ideas from the other books and applying it to life.
Indeed, I found a lot of gems, although it takes some patience to go through this thicker book (519 pages) and all the rambling and opinions of the author that are placed in between.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m sure I missed more than a few ideas, so it might be worth a second read.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<h3 id="life-philosphy">Life philosphy</h3>
<p>Stoicism is neutral to fate. Don&rsquo;t try to evade your fate but benefit from it.</p>
<p>Wealth doesn&rsquo;t make happy, because it leaves more to lose. And we are naturally more averse to losses.</p>
<p>Assume that the worst thing has already happened and everything else is a gain. This is especially important when we are doing well, since that is when we are most fragile.</p>
<p>Randomness makes life exciting. Plan less and be more spontaneous.</p>
<p>Procrastination can be a good sign to not overdo something that is not important.</p>
<p>A free person is someone who cannot be squeezed into doing something he would otherwise never do.</p>
<p>Switch the blame from the inability to see an event coming. Not seeing a tsunami or an economic event coming is excusable; building something fragile to them is not.</p>
<h3 id="barbell-effect">Barbell effect</h3>
<p>Go for the extreme, the average doesn&rsquo;t matter. Count loyal fans, don&rsquo;t care about haters.</p>
<p>Provide for the worst and let the good things take care of themselves.</p>
<p>People avoid stressors, because big stressors are harmful. We neglect that small stressors are beneficial. We don&rsquo;t grasp the non-linearity of effects.</p>
<p>Be extremely risk averse to disaster and take small risks with potential high returns on the other side. Never go for the middle.</p>
<p>Success comes with fragility: you now have a lot more to lose than to gain.</p>
<p>If you put 90 percent of your funds in boring cash and 10 percent in very risky securities, you cannot possibly lose more than 10 percent, while you are exposed to massive upside.</p>
<p>People tend to prepare for small probable risks but neglect the worst unpredictable catastrophes.</p>
<p>Being at the limit pushes ourselves. Be it innovation, muscles.. We are also more effective with our time, when we are overloaded with work.</p>
<p>Being thrown at a thousand pebbles is much less harmful than one big stone. The effect is non-linear. Many small transactions don&rsquo;t hit the market, but one huge can crush it.</p>
<p>Averages don&rsquo;t count as much, when the objective highly fluctuates around this average. Antifragility is when the average of the squares is more than the square of the averages.</p>
<h3 id="resist-your-intuition">Resist your intuition</h3>
<p>People prefer small continuous gains. On the other hand we prefer abrupt losses. Act contrary to your intuition. Make losses small (although they feel more painful) and allow for large gains (although they seem relatively less)! We have an ill sense of pain. Little harm is disproportionally more painful than big harm.</p>
<p>People avoid stressors, because big stressors are harmful. We neglect that small stressors are beneficial. We don&rsquo;t grasp the non-linearity of effects.</p>
<p>Religious fasting is a mechanism for the disease of food abundance. Varying the diet and providing stressors on the diet might be good (?)</p>
<h3 id="avoid-extreme-risk">Avoid extreme risk</h3>
<p>Don&rsquo;t let terrible things happen to you. We are in control of most things that happen. Be very risk averse against big losses.</p>
<p>Prepare for the worst instead of trying to predict the unpredictable.</p>
<p>Nature builds reserves to prepare for what is worse than before. Yet human systems are often build for &ldquo;effectiveness&rdquo;. With disastrous consequences in case of slight deviation..</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t plan on the edge. It might work for smooth conditions, but slight deviations can have disastrous results. Avoid big risks even though they are improbable. A cheap plane ticket with short connection time and tight schedule poses the risk of spending a huge amount in case of a delay.</p>
<p>Praising the benefits and efficiency of a solution should not go without including the immense cost in case of a rare failure.</p>
<h3 id="our-non-causal-world">Our non-causal world</h3>
<p>Green lumber fallacy: ignorant trader who mistakes that lumber is painted green instead of its meaning for freshness. The trader can still be very successful..</p>
<p>Knowledge is often wrongly attributed to skills. Trading requires heuristic techniques, and trade observations, not knowledge about lumber or economic theories..</p>
<p>Lumber fallacy: most expected oil prices to rise due to Kuwait war. We mistake them to be correlated, but oil price prediction doesn&rsquo;t require knowledge about the war situation in the middle east; in fact prices plumbed.</p>
<p>Leverage comes from asymmetry. Bet against the main stream??</p>
<p>As humans, we want to put everything into a narrative with causality. But are we sure that education brings wealth?</p>
<p>Influential people are not necessarily knowledgeable. Take some tech entrepreneurs, finance people..</p>
<h3 id="decision-making">Decision-making</h3>
<p>What you learn in the class room mostly remains in the class room. Most value is found outside. Learn what intrigues you, this is what will stick in your brain.</p>
<p>What most others know, will most likely not be very valuable for you. Find your own niche of skills.</p>
<p>Use simple decision-making heuristics. One argument should be enough to convince.</p>
<p>The unnatural has to prove its benefits, not the natural.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t mistake absence of evidence, for evidence of absence.</p>
<p>One cannot tell if a person with skills will succeed, but we can pretty much tell the negative. Via negative: Ask: what would lead to failure? Then avoid that.</p>
<p>Vía negativa. We know much more about what is wrong than what is right. So it is about not being wrong or stupid rather than being right and smart.</p>
<p>The learning of life is what to avoid.</p>
<p>We learn best from stressors. We benefit most from those wo tried to - but eventually failed - to harm us, rather than from those who have tried to help us (say with “advice”).</p>
<p>Decide based on fragility, not probability.</p>
<p>There is no free lunch. If you don&rsquo;t find the downside, it is most likely that there is a concealed trap somewhere.</p>
<p>Skin in the game: Hammurabi’s code: If a builder builds a house and the house collapses and causes the death of the owner of the house - the builder shall be put to death.</p>
<h3 id="subtract-dont-add">Subtract, don&rsquo;t add</h3>
<p>Knowledge grows more by subtraction. Knowing what is wrong (what to subtract) is less fragile than assertive statements.We know more about what something is not than what something is.</p>
<p>Most benefits come from subtraction. Not smoking is much more beneficial than the combination of the positive effects of many medications.</p>
<p>Living poorer than we are, might slim away many unnecessities that harm us. Trust in what is natural (it has persisted) and be sceptical of the new.</p>
<h3 id="innovation">Innovation</h3>
<p>Bottlenecks are the source of squeezes (1 percent increase in wheat demand doubled the price)</p>
<p>Innovation is about saying no to many things. Saying no to the wrong ideas is very important.</p>
<p>Technology and inventions come from tinkerers and practitioners, not theorists. Many successes are claimed to stem from scientific theories but actually they were developed afterwards. They fit a narrative in hindsight: Professor who teaches birds to fly..</p>
<p>Simple inventions like suitcase with wheels were invented after we went to the moon, even though they are so useful. It affected our lives much more than stepping on the moon.</p>
<p>The fragility of every startup is necessary for the economy to be antifragile. So some parts on the inside of a system may be required to be fragile in order to make the system antifragile as a result.</p>
<p>We rely more on water than on cell phones but because water does not change and cell phones do, we are prone to thinking that cell phones play a larger role than they do.</p>
<p>Trial and error is small loss with big gains! It wins over intelligence! Many inventions came from the prior.</p>
<h3 id="time-shows-whats-valuable">Time shows what&rsquo;s valuable</h3>
<p>The difference of perishable things and non-perishable: The life expectancy of books grows over time, whereas for technology it shrinks.</p>
<p>Be sceptical of medicine. Short term benefits might appeal, but what about long term harm? Do we really do better than Mother nature? Only in extremely ill condition, are the benefits large relative to iatrogenics (disease caused from medical treatment)..</p>
<h3 id="desire">Desire</h3>
<p>We tend to compare the differences of what seems similar and focus on the similarities of different things. This makes us desire to buy the newest and forget how we once appreciated which we know dislike about our device (smartphone.. car)</p>
<h3 id="get-as-many-options-as-possible">Get as many options as possible</h3>
<p>Always go for what provides many options.</p>
<p>The more options, the better. Be it vacation, house renting or investing. You don&rsquo;t need to be right most of the time if the upside is antisymmetric.</p>
<h3 id="act-less">Act less</h3>
<p>It’s much easier to sell “Look what I did for you” than “Look what I avoided for you.” Of course a bonus system based on “performance” exacerbates the problem.</p>
<p>Give more weight to opinions that conflict interests and favor not acting: A pharmacist who advocates starvation to cure diabetes would be more credible than one who favors the ingestion of drugs.</p>
<p>We tend to micromanage too much. The challenge is to distinguish the signal from the noise.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy - William B. Irvine</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/stoic-joy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/stoic-joy/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5617966-a-guide-to-the-good-life" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 9/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Stoicism tries to improve quality of life by becoming more appreciative about our day to day experiences.</li>
<li>Stoics mentally prepare themselves for bad things to happen, to be less affected by them and feel less regrets.</li>
<li>Stoics believe that we need to change our mind and not external conditions/circumstances to have a tranquil and happy life.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p><a href="https://fs.blog/knowledge-project/derek-sivers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://fs.blog/knowledge-project/derek-sivers/</a></p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>You want to find a philosophy of life. You want to have a more fulfilled and happier life. You think that materialism and consumerism is not the road to happiness. You want to be more robust to negative events and regret less.</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behavior / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<p>It fostered my determination on how I want to live and convinced me of Stoic principles. Without knowing, I shared many convictions before: the virtue of being frugal, purposefulness, robustness to judgement and emotions.. However, I became more aware of the power of self-control. I&rsquo;ve been trying to become more disciplined with regards to my diet, exercise and getting up early, but there are many more dimensions that can benefit from it. The ability to gain more control over our desires was eye opening to me. Also, I want to apply negative visualization to become more appreciative about the people I care about, finiteness of life, moments and activities.</p>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<p>I want to find a philosophy of life to be sure that my time is spend meaningfully. I don&rsquo;t want to regret having squandered it later.</p>
<p>Philosophy made a big leap forward around 500 BC: Pythagoras, Confucius, Buddha</p>
<p>Stoicism, unlike Cynicism, doesn&rsquo;t suggest to refrain from joy to prevent attachment to good things. Instead, it teaches to prepare ourselves for loss.</p>
<p>Religions teach how to behave morally, but not how to live a happy life.</p>
<p>Enemies are the first to discover your mistakes.</p>
<p>Hunger is the best appetizer. It makes you enjoy simple food with more pleasure.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t bother about things that are out of control.</p>
<p>Divide actions into those</p>
<ul>
<li>completely under my control</li>
<li>partial control</li>
<li>out of control</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="desires-and-life-attitude">Desires and Life attitude</h3>
<p>The easiest way to gain happiness is to want the things you already have.</p>
<p>Human desire is insatiable. After getting what we want, we lose interest and desire the next thing.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t bother about things that are out of control. Divide actions into complete/partial/no control.</p>
<p>Internalize goals that are under partial control. E.g being loved is not under my control, but being a good lover is totally internal.</p>
<p>Expect bad things to happen. Misfortune hurts most when we expect good fortune.</p>
<p>Negative visualization: each time might be the last one. Imagine the loss of what you value - beloved ones, activities, abilities, possessions. How would you feel if you become blind or lose freedom? Considering this makes you cherish those moments more and prevents later regrets when things are gone.</p>
<h3 id="self-control">Self-control</h3>
<p>Practice poverty from time to time. See how cheap things can make you happy.</p>
<p>Wealth is not worth pursuing if we reject pursuing fame. Spending doesn&rsquo;t make happy, in that it raises our benchmarks to be happy. It&rsquo;s a blessing to be happy with simple food, because it is hard to lose. Whereas, luxury is easy to slip away and makes us crave for bigger things.</p>
<p>Hunger is the best appetizer. It makes you enjoy simple food with more pleasure.</p>
<p>Food is an especially dangerous pleasure, because we are exposed to it every day. Keep food, living and clothing practical.</p>
<p>Occasionally resist pleasure to train self-control. The goal is to internalize happiness and indulgence is an external pleasure. E.g. resisting to eat an ice cream makes us forego the culinary pleasure of sweetness but it brings the pleasure of self-control.</p>
<p>Our desire for pleasures tend to be short sighted, bearing long term costs. While self-control takes effort, not having it is also expensive. Think of all the trouble coming from affairs, drugs, food&hellip;</p>
<p>Put yourself in discomfort: do exercise, wear too little clothes, resist eating.. Enjoy the achievement of self-control.</p>
<p>When wanting to buy something, ask if this will make you happier.</p>
<h3 id="momento-mori">Momento mori</h3>
<p>Everything is ephemeral: Being with my family; Showing love to people I like; Dancing; Sports; Enjoying good weather. Remind yourself how they make you happy without attaching to them.</p>
<p>You probably have a lot of what you dreamed of in the past. Did the desires fulfill you long term?</p>
<p>You likely take for granted things that your ancestors dreamt of and never had.</p>
<p>Gain happiness by changing yourself. Want only those things that are easy to obtain.</p>
<p>Happiness is, to a great extent, not dependent on external living conditions. Happiness is about being content with how things are and this is more about training the mind than trying to get more from the outside world.</p>
<p>Focus your energy on what you genuinely value and be indifferent about the rest. Most &ldquo;bad&rdquo; things are not really that bad&hellip;</p>
<p>Be fatalistic about the past. Don&rsquo;t think about how things could have been better.</p>
<p>Find delight in your own resources, and desire no joys greater than your inner joys.</p>
<p>Stoics are not afraid of dying, because life is finite. A life with meaning and engagement in ones duties is worth dying when the time has come. They are willing to sacrifice their life for their principles. For them, a life that has nothing to be worth dying for is not worth anything.</p>
<p>Observe what older people are taken away from because of their health condition, and visualize how you might feel without it. It makes you appreciate having it, but realize how you could also live without it.</p>
<p>When older people complain about aging, make them realize how it could be worse.</p>
<h3 id="society">Society</h3>
<p>Friendship and love bring much joy, but they are also the cause of our greatest discomfort and pain. Peoples behavior bothers us and we are anxious about social expectations.</p>
<p>Instead of escaping human interaction, we should see it as our duty. We are stronger together and have to strive for harmony to benefit each other. Show love to the people around you.</p>
<p>Avoid people with unclean principles, because it will affect ourselves. Those with unwholesome desires, who whine and complain, because it disrupts your tranquility.</p>
<p>When you feel annoyed about other people&rsquo;s defects, think about your defects. For your mental tranquility, assume that they are destined to behave like this, but help to invoke change. People can change.</p>
<p>Be silent when people chit-chat and try to change the topic toward something more interesting.</p>
<p>Prepare for social interaction. Develop your own personality while being alone and stick to yourself when socializing. Set rules and remain true to your principles.</p>
<p>In a good marriage, two people will join in a loving union and will try to outdo each other in the care they show for each other.</p>
<h3 id="dealing-with-emotions">Dealing with emotions</h3>
<p>Sex is likely to do more harm than good. Who says that life would have been easier if he were more sexually active? But how often is the reverse true? Unwanted pregnancy..</p>
<p>To maintain self-control over lust, it is helpful to analyze how primitive and mundane our desires are: Sex is no more than friction with ejaculatory discharge..</p>
<p>Our natural impulses to have sex, to desire, feel insulted by other people&rsquo;s opinion are driven by evolution, not to have a tranquil life. But we can use our reasoning to resist and pursue tranquility instead.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t take insults personally. Showing indifference is most effective. If they are foolish, deflect the insult with humor. If you don&rsquo;t know how to respond, ignore it and keep silent.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t take other people&rsquo;s praise nor disapproval. Seeking social status means externalizing our luck, which is out of our control.</p>
<p>When a friend feels grieve, grieving with him is like drinking poison after he was poisoned. The goal is to make him feel better, not to make us feel miserable as well. And we are likely to be much more helpful if we don&rsquo;t let our feelings be disturbed.</p>
<p>Modern philosophy suggests forcing grieve and talking to friends and a psychologist as a mean of processing it. Stoicism tries to make us feel better through reflection and reasoning. Would that person want me to be sad?</p>
<h3 id="bedtime-meditation">Bedtime meditation</h3>
<p>Before going to bed, ask these questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>What upset me?</li>
<li>What failed?</li>
<li>How can I improve?</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="living-like-a-stoic">Living like a stoic</h3>
<ol>
<li>Practice negative visualization. Set a time and situation. On commute? Before sleep?</li>
<li>Focus on goals under our control and internalize them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t dwell on the past or how things could have been better.</li>
<li>Practice self-denial to gain self-control.</li>
</ol>
]]></description></item><item><title>Deep Work - Cal Newport</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/deepwork/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/deepwork/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25744928-deep-work" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 9/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Finding focus to think deeply is a hard with the distractions of ubiquitous connectivity today.</li>
<li>Concentration and focus can be trained and hugely supported through habits.</li>
<li>Deep work makes happy and leaves more time for other things in life</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>Knowledge workers who want to be more productive at their work. Those seeking techniques and inspiration to find more focus and train concentration.</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behaviour / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<p>I strive to be excellent in my profession. This requires focused, deliberate practice. I therefore design my day to make full use of my concentration capacity by blocking it and removing any distractions. Rituals and routines should help me to stick to it.</p>
<h2 id="-what-do-i-want-to-apply-to-my-life">👷🏼 What do I want to apply to my life?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Experiment with routines and rituals before and after deep work</li>
<li>Plan the deep session and reserve time blocks the day before</li>
<li>Try out the &ldquo;productive walk&rdquo;: choose a problem and go out walking to ponder</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<h3 id="what-is-deep-work-and-for-whom-is-it">What is Deep work and for whom is it?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Deep Work: Professional activities performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limit.</li>
<li>Batch hard tasks into long, uninterrupted stretches.</li>
<li>The amount of deep work of professionals seems to be limited to up to 4h on one day.</li>
<li>Deep work doesn&rsquo;t work for all professions. Salesmen and CEOs are responsible for a lot of different tasks and need to make quick decisions and be highly available</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="focus-on-few-things-and-fully-engage-with-them">Focus on few things and fully engage with them</h3>
<ul>
<li>Deeply focus on one thing at a time: the brain forms wrapping layers of myelin around the neuron circuits that fire intensively. If distracted, the neural activity is too disperse to strengthen the area for your desired skill.</li>
<li>Minimize the amount of tasks to avoid attention leakage (things that are not yet fully dealt with will occupy your mind and distract).</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="resisting-shallow-work-is-hard">Resisting shallow work is hard</h3>
<ul>
<li>It is natural to feel the desire to relieve ourselves from hard work. Smart habits are the way to combat them.</li>
<li>The principle of least resistance: it&rsquo;s easier to be suggested what to do next (e.g. by checking inbox or messages) vs actively choosing and planning the prioritized work</li>
<li>A difficulty of knowledge work is that it&rsquo;s results are not always easily quantifiable and appreciable compared to manual work such as craftsmanship. This makes us incline more towards doing quantifiable shallow tasks like answering emails or attending meetings.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="deep-work-makes-happy">Deep work makes happy</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Our brains construct our worldview based on what we pay attention to. This contradicts the common belief that the small details of how we spend our day don&rsquo;t matter, because it&rsquo;s all about the large-scale outcomes. (That&rsquo;s analogous to the picture analogy. We tell stories about the big picture, but we really live in the small pixels).
We cannot always change the circumstances, but we can influence how we perceive it, e.g. by enjoying the small things (pixels) in life. Even if we have a serious disease, our picture is still made up of many, many pixels that we can appreciate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Who you are, what you think, feel, and do, what you love — is the sum of what you focus on.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Winifred Gallagher</em></p>
<p>Our focus can provide a significant leverage on a positive attitude.</p>
<p>Example: &ldquo;Rather than focusing on your partners selfishness and sloth, you might instead focus on the fact that a festering conflict has been aired, which is the first step toward a solution and to your improved mood.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When we spend a significant amount of time working with full dedication, it will feel important to us. If we spend enough time in this state of deep focus, our worldview will adopt this perspective as well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It also leaves less space for less pleasant things&hellip; The idle mind is the devils&rsquo; workshop: when you lose focus, you are mind tends to fix on what&rsquo;s wrong. So being focused and limiting input, leaves less space for this</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Research shows that elderly people have learned to respond more strongly to positive imagery.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Being in a flow (be absorbed by the moment) makes us most happy. &ldquo;The best moments usually occur, when we are voluntarily stretched to our limits to achieve something difficult and worthwhile&rdquo;. This contradicts the common belief that relaxation is bliss.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Work is easier to be enjoyable than free time, because it&rsquo;s structured and challenging:</p>
<p>&ldquo;work usually has built-in goals, feedback rules, challenges, all of which encourage one to become involved and lose oneself in it&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your work is craft and honing that skill and appreciating its &ldquo;art&rdquo; makes it meaningful:</p>
<p>&ldquo;The meaningfulness uncovered by such efforts is due to the skill and appreciation inherent in craftsmanship — not the outcomes of the work.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Following this argument, deep work can be the source for a satisfying career. Instead of following &ldquo;your passion&rdquo; in your career, its more helpful to pursue the craftsmanship ideals.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="find-your-deep-work-philosophy">Find your deep work philosophy</h3>
<p><strong>Styles:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Monastic: isolate as much from outside distractions as possible</li>
<li>Bimodal: not everyone can afford complete absence due to substantial commitments. They therefore occasionally (e.g. monthly) dedicate extensive stretches of at least one day to work deeply.</li>
<li>Rhythmic: transform deep work into a simple regular habit by reserving a fixed time for it. It ensures consistent progress.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="techniques-to-foster-deep-work">Techniques to foster deep work</h3>
<p><strong>Routines:</strong></p>
<p>Minimize the amount of willpower necessary to maintain unbroken concentration through preparation and routines:
<strong>Where and for how long?</strong>
try to have a dedicated place. Define an end time!</p>
<p><strong>How will you work once you start?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>define taboos and metrics. Otherwise, you will have to mentally litigate what you should and should not be doing</li>
<li>reduce the amount of willpower needed:
no phone, no mail</li>
<li>No easy tasks that don&rsquo;t require full attention.
<strong>How will you support your work?</strong></li>
<li>I like to start with cup of tea. Have everything I need at one place. Do light yoga pauses to move.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Collaboration:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>working together can be helpful to deep focus for certain problems. The presence of the other waiting for your next insight can push you into deeper focus — avoiding the natural instinct to avoid depth.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Grand gesture:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>radical change to normal environment coupled with significant investment of effort or money to support a deep work task</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Stay on track:</strong> 4 Techniques by Clayton Chirstensen:</p>
<p><strong>#1 Focus on the Wildly Important</strong></p>
<p><strong>#2 Act on the Lead Measures</strong></p>
<p>There exist lag and lead motivators. Lag motivators describe what you are ultimately trying to achieve, but they come too late to motivate persistence. Lead measures focus on the new behaviors that will help you reach your goal. Therefore, act on the latter. E.g. by tracking deep work hours.</p>
<p><strong>#3 Track your metrics consistently</strong></p>
<p>Log deep work hours consistently and evaluate how to improve and what to keep. Mark milestones and reward yourself.</p>
<p><strong>#4 Create a Cadence of Accountability</strong></p>
<p>Keep yourself accountable with weekly reviews.</p>
<p><strong>Productive meditation:</strong></p>
<p>Engage physically e.g. walking, jogging, driving, showering - and focus your attention on a single well-defined professional problem.
Its main purpose is to train deep thinking.</p>
<p>Steps to do before:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Review the relevant variables (options)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Define the next-step question using these variables ( How? What might go wrong?)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Example: “How am I going to effectively open this chapter?”. This provides a specific target for your attention.
Be aware that we tend to repeat what we already know! Remind that you can come back to this idea later and bring the attention back.
Initially we tend to derail our attention to other seemingly important tasks. Resists this urge! That&rsquo;s the whole point of this exercise.
The final step is to consolidate your gains by reviewing clearly the answer you identified.</p>
<h3 id="the-mind-needs-rest">The mind needs rest</h3>
<p>Some decisions are better left to your unconscious.
For decisions that involve large amounts of information and multiple vague, and perhaps even conflicting, constraints, use your unconscious.</p>
<p>Rest doesn&rsquo;t mean being lazy but switching to something else. In fact, I feel better the next day when I spent my leisure time doing other challenging things as opposed to hanging around lazily. → Substitute distractions with quality alternatives for the brain.</p>
<p>Spending time in nature can improve your ability to concentrate.</p>
<p>Trying to squeeze a little more work out of your evenings might reduce your effectiveness the next day.</p>
<h3 id="have-a-fixed-feierabend-time">Have a fixed Feierabend time</h3>
<p>Finish work at five thirty: This strong break lets you avoid taking up shallow commitments.
Be strict about not allowing professional concerns after workday shut down.
Even short distractions might impede the shutdown advantages.</p>
<p>Have a shutdown ritual: Capture every incomplete task, so that you don&rsquo;t need to worry about it after work.</p>
<p>Put more thought into your leisure time. What fulfills you and makes you happy?</p>
<p>Be pragmatic but critical about sticking to your schedule: an important insight or high drive to do an unscheduled task is a perfectly valid reason to ignore the schedule.</p>
<h3 id="reduce-the-time-on-shallow-tasks">Reduce the time on shallow tasks</h3>
<p>Be intentional and selective about communication:</p>
<ul>
<li>Limit email communication. Don&rsquo;t reply if a reply requires too much effort (too unconcrete) or if a reply doesn&rsquo;t promise any benefit. Can anything good happen if I reply?</li>
<li>Before quickly replying, take a minute to think how to most effectively bring the &ldquo;project&rdquo; (as defined in GTD) implied by the message to a successful conclusion. Be concrete, assertive and don&rsquo;t leave open questions.</li>
<li>Steps to respond:
<ol>
<li>Describe the process you identified.</li>
<li>Point out the current step.</li>
<li>Emphasize the next step.
The recipient should find it easy to reply.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When writing emails, succinctly explain your concern and why the recipient should react to it. How can he benefit? Make a concrete proposal for how to proceed. Don&rsquo;t leave open loops.</p>
<h3 id="others">Others</h3>
<p>Concentration is like a muscle that requires practice. It gets very hard if you are used to being distracted → make consistent efforts instead of trying hard during a short period of time.</p>
<p>Ambitious self-imposed deadlines help to force concentration.</p>
<p>Schedule an occasional break from focus to give in to distraction, instead of forcing yourself to resist distraction during a time period.</p>
<p>Selective tool choices: Adopt a tool only if its positive impacts substantially outweigh the negative.</p>
<p>For each goal define the two or three most important activities to reach it.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>The Psychology of Money - Morgan Housel</title><link>https://astobbe.me/books/psychology-of-money/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/books/psychology-of-money/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>




</p>
<p>🔗 Link : <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41881472-the-psychology-of-money" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Goodreads</a></p>
<p>⭐️ Rating: 7/10</p>
<h2 id="-the-book-in-3-sentences">🚀 The Book in 3 Sentences</h2>
<ol>
<li>Accept the human psychology when investing: it&rsquo;s not about maximum return but about what we feel best with</li>
<li>Invest for the long term and broadly: the compounding effect is huge and it&rsquo;s the tails who make the big gains</li>
<li>Wealth is money not spent. It instead gives you control over your life, which is the biggest factor for happiness.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="-impressions">🎨 Impressions</h2>
<h3 id="how-i-discovered-it">How I Discovered It</h3>
<p><a href="https://aliabdaal.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Ali Abdaal</a></p>
<h3 id="who-should-read-it">Who Should Read It?</h3>
<p>Everyone who is not convinced of passive long term investing.</p>
<h2 id="-how-the-book-changed-me">☘️ How the Book Changed Me</h2>
<p>How my life / behaviour / thoughts / ideas have changed as a result of reading the book.</p>
<ul>
<li>It is important to start investing very early: don&rsquo;t neglect the contributions  from my small initial investments</li>
<li>I want to spend money on what lets me spend my time in the most meaningful way. I am willing to pay for stuff I can do myself but is hard for me or dull, e.g. repairs, repetitive tasks</li>
<li>Market volatility is a fee and not a fine. It&rsquo;s the fee you pay to get access to high returns. Not a fine for taking risks.</li>
<li>Bet on the success of the few. Failures don&rsquo;t matter if they finally somehow lead to success. Taking risks makes success more likely and failures are normal. But never risk failures that could destroy you completely.</li>
<li>Also invest during bear market (time is your best friend ).</li>
<li>Keep your expectations low. Wealth is not just about income but also about our spending behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="-summary--notes">📒 Summary + Notes</h2>
<p>Our notion of investing is hugely affected by the environment. Growing up in a bull market vs depression.</p>
<p>Compound effects are extreme and are the key factor for Warren buffets success. The key is to maintain assets for them to grow over time.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the tails who make the big gains. Consistently invest also during bear market.</p>
<p>The reasonable wins over the rational strategy because you are more likely to persist with the former. Theoretically best to invest with 50 debt ratio in early years, including bear market, but take the option you sleep well with.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a fallacy to believe that we remain the person we are right now. Therefore, it&rsquo;s good to save without knowing for what.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t worry about sunk cost, it&rsquo;s about the future and not past efforts. Don&rsquo;t go for extremes and bet on a bright future.</p>
<p>The price of a stock depends on your time horizon. Do you want to sell in a year, in a decade?</p>
<p>Humans are risk averse. Therefore, pessimistic news gain more attention. Whereas huge successes such as a big company growth in a few months may go unnoticed</p>
<p>We warp reality around our beliefs / wishes. If we believe that a recession is about to come, we take every sign as a confirmation, although there might be nothing behind it.. We are less critical in that situation.</p>
<p>Risk is what is left when you think you have thought of everything. We don&rsquo;t tend to accept the complexity of the world, but rather make the world fit our narrative. We need to come to terms with how much is out of our control</p>
<p>Define the rules by which you play and make sure you don&rsquo;t follow others who have different rules / goals. Bubble speculators&hellip;</p>
<p>Independence is the highest goal. It&rsquo;s about keeping expectations low to save enough.</p>
<p>Make decisions you feel good with. It is not rational to pay a house when interest rates are low, but it gives you the feeling of liberty.
Same for cash. Keep a money reserve to decrease the likelihood to sell stocks for big investment.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>