<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Programming - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/categories/programming/</link><description>Programming - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/categories/programming/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Tutorial]: K8s Monitoring with InfluxDB's Telegraf</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/k8s-monitoring-with-influx-telegraf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/k8s-monitoring-with-influx-telegraf/</guid><description>InfluxDB is an Open-Source timeseries database which can be used for monitoring Kubernetes clusters. In this tutorial, I want to show you step by step how to get a dashboard with metrics on Kuberntes resource usage of podes and nodes. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult, but the official documentation is outdated and confusing, so I hope to make it easier for you. We will use InfluxDB2 which includes a nice dashboard and supports the Flux QL query language.</description></item><item><title>Testable code has few mocks</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/js-testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/js-testing/</guid><description>Testing can sometimes seem hard and tedious. We might be faced with complex setup logic and many mocks. But this is a smell of poor code design. When properly done, mocks are rarely needed. TDD helps to avoid tight coupling and it naturally tends towards functional code. In this post, I cover how the functional style leads to less error prone code and fewer code to be tested. Moreover, we will explore when it is proper to use mocks.</description></item><item><title>Tools and shortcuts for MacOS</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/tools-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/tools-mac/</guid><description>After many years of Windows, I switched to MacOS this year - with no regrets. Besides the big plus of being UNIX-based, I got to appreciate the user-friendliness and smooth integrations with the iPad. My favourites are using the iPad as an external sreen, Airdrop, signing documents and continuity.
But the system switch, also made me find new ways to interact with it. In the following I want to show a few tools and shortcuts that optimize my workflow on the Mac:</description></item><item><title>Unix cheatsheet - Beyond the basics</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</guid><description>We developers use the terminal a lot and there are a lot of tricks that can ease our work. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking beyond the essentials of getting stuff done in the shell! The quickest way to find what you need is probably to use tldr. But the frequently used hacks are best learned once to know about all the good stuff and work effectively. I recently found the great The Linux Command Handbook from Freecodecamp and went over it to extract the useful bites that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Fixing CSV parsing - First attribute not regonized (BOM)</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</guid><description>Today, I wanted to read a CSV file from Notion and stumbled on the issue that my first attribute was not properly read. I validated my code on a another file before, but on this file it just didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Turns out that I had the same issue with another npm library. What bothered me was that when printing the object, I could see the attribute, but it had single quotes around it and was printed in green.</description></item><item><title>CKAD preparation - Tips for the Kubernetes exam</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</guid><description>Recently, I took the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exam and would like to share some tips for the preparation. Be aware that at the end of September, an updated 2021 version will be released, so contents will change a bit. Nevertheless, the exam contains 20 questions that need to be completed in 2 hours. So its crucial to be quick and comfortable with the kubectl CLI and formatting yaml files. But first things first:</description></item><item><title>VIM - Why geeks love it and you will too</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</guid><description><![CDATA[VIM is more than just a text editor for geeks and the cool kids! If you aren&rsquo;t convinced or haven&rsquo;t heard about it - stick with me to see how it&rsquo;s magic might also improve your typing experience.
Also, VIM is absolutely worth learning if you don&rsquo;t intend to use the terminal program! Because of its vibrant community, VIM features are also supported in popular IDEs like Visual Studio Code (the best of both worlds imho) or even your Browser.]]></description></item><item><title>Design Patterns: How to write better code</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 09:18:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Learning to write proper code is hard. Who doesn&rsquo;t know it, after having an initial spark on how to solve a problem, it is tentative to immediately start coding.</p>
<p>I guess most of us did so initially and almost always ended up on dead-end roads. Taking the time to think a design through before writing the first line is indispensable for larger projects but even makes things easier for smaller undertakings.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>