<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Programming - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/categories/programming/</link><description>Programming - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/categories/programming/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CKAD preparation - Tips for the Kubernetes exam</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</guid><description>Recently, I took the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exam and would like to share some tips for the preparation. Be aware that at the end of September, an updated 2021 version will be released, so contents will change a bit. Nevertheless, the exam contains 20 questions that need to be completed in 2 hours. So its crucial to be quick and comfortable with the kubectl CLI and formatting yaml files. But first things first:</description></item><item><title>VIM - Why geeks love it and you will too</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</guid><description><![CDATA[VIM is more than just a text editor for geeks and the cool kids! If you aren&rsquo;t convinced or haven&rsquo;t heard about it - stick with me to see how it&rsquo;s magic might also improve your typing experience.
Also, VIM is absolutely worth learning if you don&rsquo;t intend to use the terminal program! Because of its vibrant community, VIM features are also supported in popular IDEs like Visual Studio Code (the best of both worlds imho) or even your Browser.]]></description></item><item><title>Design Patterns: How to write better code</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 09:18:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Learning to write proper code is hard. Who doesn&rsquo;t know it, after having an initial spark on how to solve a problem, it is tentative to immediately start coding.</p>
<p>I guess most of us did so initially and almost always ended up on dead-end roads. Taking the time to think a design through before writing the first line is indispensable for larger projects but even makes things easier for smaller undertakings.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>