<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Me - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/categories/me/</link><description>Me - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/categories/me/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semi Annual Review 2022</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/semi-annual-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/semi-annual-2022/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="how-did-the-first-half-go">How did the first half go?</h2>
<p>2022 is maybe the most exciting year so far.
I spent January still on my Erasmus semester in Barcelona. I had exams this month, but I still made time to explore new things. I had my first deprivation tank experience, tried light therapy glasses and went to a magic show by <a href="https://www.luispardo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Luis Pardo</a>.
<figure>
</figure>
</p>
<p>I challenged myself to talk to a stranger every day: and found out that most people actually enjoy small talk. It opens for serendipity: I got to meet a guy on the subway who is from the same small town in Cadiz where I would go in a few weeks.</p>
<p>Living in places, not as a tourist, but by staying there for some time, is how I like to explore.
After Beijing, Munich and Barcelona, I decided to go for my first digital nomad experience.
I went to Cadiz in the sunny south of Spain for about 4 weeks. I loved the proximity to the sea in Barcelona, but I wanted to explore a more tranquile and nature-based place.
A free room in an apartment with a charming lady in her fifties (it&rsquo;s rude to ask the age right) brought me to El Puerto de Santa Maria. A small town at the coast line facing the peninsula of the city Cadiz. I am happy I did it and I learned a few things about myself and on how I want to live:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This year, I lived my first month as a digital nomad in Spain, Cadiz.<br>I lived in a small town called El puerto in a shared flat with an older lady. These are my takeaways:</p>&mdash; Adrian Stobbe (@astobbe_) <a href="https://twitter.com/astobbe_/status/1500104636090531854?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 5, 2022</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>I did a windsurf course, enjoyed bathing in the sea in the late afternoon, and taking walks.
I hope I documented more of my experience, but I particularly remember the horse riding day with Johanna and the day at the beautiful, mostly untouched beach in Los Caños de Meca. My nice host Lola proposed the trip and brought me and my friends Stefan and Juno from the windsurf course there by car (you need a car in Andalusia!).
I remember the adventurous mountain trip to a beautiful lagoon in Algeciras with Hector and the monkey day at the rock of Gibraltar.</p>
<p><figure>
</figure>

<figure>
</figure>

<figure>
</figure>
</p>
<p>At the end of the month, I returned to Munich for an exam and got to see my friends again. I truly enjoyed my days with them and realized how my friendships had improved. I went skiing for the first time in my life with my old school friend Maxi.</p>
<figure>
</figure>

<p>And March was yet another great month. I got back to my family in Berlin and enjoyed Urban sports to the fullest. I went to lots of dancing classes, swimming, to the gym + sauna and I went on a bouldering date with a special person.
On this date, I met a midwestern girl that for the first time ever gave me the feeling of a soulmate. We think alike in so many ways: the curiosity to explore new places and perspectives, being intentional, the desire for deep connection&hellip; I could go on, but I spare you the rest.
I got hella lucky to meet this girl on a dating app: Bumble (yeah did not expect this neither).
We bonded in no time and everything just seemed right.
In June I went to see her family in the U.S. and had a wonderful time. I was surprised to find bigger cultural differences than I expected and changed my perspective on how I want to treat my family and see my friends. I learned a lot about <a href="https://astobbe.me/letters/love-and-feel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">my emotions</a> and the value of <a href="https://astobbe.me/letters/thinking-out-loud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">thinking out loud</a>.
My highlights were the days at the family&rsquo;s cabin by a lake, and the camping night at Lake Superior.
Shaped by the car dependence in the U.S. and earlier in Cadiz, I was more determined than ever to get my driver&rsquo;s license and finally started when I got back.
In June, I also moved into my own flat in the heart of Berlin. Growing up in the suburbs of Berlin, its quite another experience to live in the most buzzing place and getting everywhere within much fewer time. Shortened commute time is worth a lot, because commute often was an impediment to go out in the first place. Now I miss the greenery at times, but you can&rsquo;t have it all. As I recently learned, Berlin is one of the greenest cities in Europe, so I just need to take advantage of the many parks.</p>
<h2 id="status-update-of-my-life-areas-and-goals">Status update of my life areas and goals</h2>
<h3 id="life">Life</h3>
<p>I appreciate to be close to my family, because I know it won&rsquo;t be permanent. I feel fortunate to live by mself in a place that is so close to work and central. A wonderful human being entered my life this year and I am learning so much about my emotions and childhood distortions (nothing dramatic, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GFKzE52XRmw&amp;ab_channel=TheSchoolofLife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">everyone has them</a> 😉 ).</p>
<p>After my thesis submission, I want to consciously take more time to do things I tend to put off because x needs to be done first. I want to live my life today and not postpone it to the future.
I want to try new things, do trips, invest in deep friendships, visit the people I care about.</p>
<h3 id="career">Career</h3>
<p>I set the goal to do 7 learning projects this year.
So far, I did:</p>
<ul>
<li>finish my <a href="https://github.com/elchead/people" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">first offline PWA (progressive web app)</a>: I am still not 100% happy with the app and it has some issues on Safari iOS lately. I&rsquo;m thinking about switching to Obsidian, but the learning experience with Typescript and PWA features was the main motivation.</li>
<li>learn rust: read <a href="https://www.manning.com/books/rust-in-action" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Rust in Action</a>; completed all <a href="https://github.com/elchead/rustlings-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">rustlings exercises</a></li>
<li>went to <a href="https://www.wearedevelopers.com/world-congress/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">We are devs</a> conference. I realized that I miss out on a lot of events in my tech sphere, because I don&rsquo;t keep myself up-to-date. I found out too late that KubeCon was in Valencia this year. I would have loved to go. I want to stay more informed through Twitter (how I found we are devs), maybe LinkedIn and tech communities (meetup? online?). If you have any recommendations, please tell me :)</li>
<li>continue Uncle Bobs <a href="https://learning.oreilly.com/videos/clean-code-fundamentals/9780134661742/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Clean Code Fundamentals</a> video course: it&rsquo;s highly entertaining and I have lots to learn. I stopped watching the course due to thesis pressure and other priorities, but I want to continue, refine my notes and eventually share them on the blog</li>
</ul>
<p>I am interested to explore:</p>
<ul>
<li>practice my vim / IDE shorcut skills. I want to explore another IDE than VS Code that has more powerful refactoring and automation capabilities (thinking of Jetbrains)</li>
<li>explore optimizations in the terminal. Starting last year, I leveled up my terminal with oh-my-zsh and some nice plugins, but I am still not using it to the fullest. I know about fzf but I don&rsquo;t use it. Here are <a href="https://github.com/elchead/dotfiles/tree/main" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">my dotfiles</a>. If you have any plugin recommendation, please reach out :) I am also curious on the <a href="https://www.warp.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">warp project</a> and might try it out</li>
<li>learn about web3: the space and innovations going on.. On the tech side, I want to learn about substrate and polkadot. I visited a <a href="https://substrate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">substrate</a> workshop earlier and want to get involved in a project.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="habits">Habits</h3>
<p>I see habits as the empowerment for positive change. Taking a learning hour off in the morning is the first step to reach my goal on the learning projects. Setting a rule to get to bed by 22.30 pm is my condition for a good start of the day and being productive.
Yet, I am not particularily consistent.
The only habit I am fairly consistent with is practicing Ukulele: it takes only few minutes and is fun.
As part of my <a href="https://astobbe.me/posts/2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">yearly goals</a>, I decided to do a sweet free month and failed. My longest streak was 7 days, because of single days where I failed (also due to social pressure ^^). I only recorded 32 sweet free days this year until know.</p>
<p>My most important habit is journaling and while I almost always do it in the morning, the more important day reflection is in the evening, where I often fail. Mostly, I lack energy and am not in thinking mood. I need to take my winddown routine (yoga streching, meditation, chill music) more seriously. I also recently discovered<a href="https://twitter.com/astobbe_/status/1552346810974408706" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer"> iPhone + keyboard </a> as a good mobile combination that works on public transport and avoids big bright light before going to bed. I just bought a stand for my iPhone - let&rsquo;s see how that goes.
I generally find myself to have low self-discipline in the evening (quite understandably as a morning person..) and often also don&rsquo;t go to bed on time.</p>
<p>As a summary:</p>
<ul>
<li>I want to be persistent with not allowing distractions in the morning. No phone in the morning (until 10am at least)</li>
<li>I need to acknowledge my low self-discipline at night and rely more on my sleep reminder to tell me to winddown. I want to incorporate yoga streching to see if it helps with sleep. I also experimented with theanine, but it seems to make me feel very sleepy in the morning and live stronger dreams. I want to sleep by 22.30 pm latest.</li>
<li>I want to meditate every day.</li>
<li>I want to try the no-sweet challenge again</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="writing">Writing</h3>
<p>I already wrote 9 blog plosts this year, 8 letters and published 5 book notes. This is more than last year, and I also got two positive feedbacks from strangers so far. I recently started tracking my blog analytics and found out that I get some fair traffic from Google and most of it on my <a href="https://astobbe.me/posts/building-a-journaling-habit-with-obsidian/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Obsidian article on Journaling</a>. So far, I&rsquo;ve been mostly writing for myself and I want to keep it that way. However, I want to practice my writing style and build a small audience.</p>
<p>Inspired by Jen Vermet, I am thinking of joining the <a href="https://writeofpassage.school/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Write of Passage</a> (if I get a scholarship). I also want to get some tips and feedback from writing friends. Maybe, I would like to be more active in an online-community. I recently joined <a href="https://nesslabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Nesslabs</a>.</p>
<h2 id="learnings">Learnings</h2>
<p>Say no. I still find myself comitting and saying yes to things I don&rsquo;t want. Don&rsquo;t make spontaneous, impulsive decision-making. Rather defer it and think about it in a quiet moment.</p>
<p>Being over doing. I feel I constantly have to do something. But sometimes it&rsquo;s just nice to be with myself and feel my emotions. I often catch myself escaping my emotions.</p>
<p>Procrastination is a natural protection. I constantly tend to put too much stuff on my todos. I don&rsquo;t need to feel bad that I can&rsquo;t do it all. Many of it, feels exciting or important in the moment, but if it is really important to me just shows when I gain more distance from the thought. Do less and fully engage in what I do.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t make it too delicious. I want to eat to feel good afterwards not to feel good in the moment. I often tend to eat too much in a single meal and feel tired afterwards. Eating something less delicious (usually also more healthy..) helps to eat for my health instead of against it.</p>
<p>Coffee is a potent drug for me. I get into highly focused states and have almost ecstatic levels of happiness at times. I need to be careful with it because it also causes diarrea (caffeine increases colonic activity..) and it seems to have a very long half life for me, which can interfere with my sleep.</p>
<p>Start the day early and with intention. It makes me feel much better.</p>
<h2 id="thought-bits">Thought bits</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been meaning to do an <a href="https://jamesclear.com/2016-integrity-report" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">integrity report</a> ever since I read <a href="https://astobbe.me/books/atomic-habits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Atomic habits</a> and plan to do it (at least by the end of this year 😉).
The core questions are:</p>
<ol>
<li>What are the core values that drive my life and work?</li>
<li>How am I living and working with integrity right now?</li>
<li>How can I set a higher standard in the future?</li>
</ol>
<p>Lastly, I want to thank Jen Vermet, who reminded me to do this (yeah, it&rsquo;s almost August already) through her <a href="https://learnitalletter.substack.com/p/-letter-119-my-semi-annual-review" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">review letter</a>. I highly recommend her newsletter. Her letters are very introspective, personal and a great inspiration for me.</p>
<hr>
<p>I&rsquo;m excited for what&rsquo;s to come in the 5 remaining months and you can expect my annual review at the end of the year!
I want to finish off with a nice quote from an email signature that Michael Pollan read many years ago:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I hope whatever you are doing , you stop once in awhile and not doing it at all
<cite>- The mind on plants, Michael Pollan</cite></p>
</blockquote>
]]></description></item><item><title>My semester in Barcelona</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/erasmus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/erasmus/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Last September, I moved to Barcelona for an exchange semester at UPC.
Now that I&rsquo;m leaving the city, I want to look back on the past months.</p>
<p>Living in Spain was a dream come true. Since I was little, I felt attracted to the country: the people, the language and the weather.
Barcelona was an obvious choice after falling in love with the city and making a good friend there in 2018.
I wanted to take these months for exploration and self discovery. I paused my work contract to find time for side projects and to go out.</p>
<h2 id="living-with-roomies">Living with roomies</h2>
<p>I moved in a shared flat with my friend which was also my first true roomie experience. After living alone for more than a year, I got to enjoy the solitude, but  it was interesting to live in a more lively environment. Living under the same roof with someone provides a deep view into how they live and deal with all kinds of daily situations.
As a result, I adopted some of their behaviors - some intentionally, some unconsciously.
Two of my roommates are a couple and I liked how openly they would discuss their worries and feelings.
I come from a family where we did not share much personal feelings, so I tend to choke them up, but my roomie told me how good it feels to vent off and not let problems accumulate.
There is a healthy limit of course, but I agree and have been opening up on my inner thoughts.</p>
<h2 id="eating-vegan">Eating vegan</h2>
<p>Secondly, I got into veganism through my roommates. They are good and healthy cooks and I liked to explore new meals. I started eating more vegetables (steamed 👌) and got new food inspirations. I realized how I could mostly drop all of the non-vegan stuff and find good substitutes. I already mostly avoided meat before (for health and ethical reasons) but consumed lots of dairies, eggs etc.
My friend raised my awareness for how I equally support industrial livestock farming with those animal products, just like meat.
I did not become vegan, but I&rsquo;ve set it as my baseline.</p>
<h2 id="side-projects">Side projects</h2>
<p>Working on my own projects was challenging and highly rewarding at the same time. It&rsquo;s challenging because there is no one to keep you responsible and motivated. On the other hand, finishing a project pushes the confidence in one&rsquo;s own skills and seeing people star the project, because they might potentially find it useful, feels great. My biggest project was my personal search engine <a href="https://github.com/elchead/misou" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">misou</a>. It started as a Hackathon project with some friends from uni and I continued working on it to practice and make it usable.
On the side, I was reading O&rsquo;reilly literature on TDD, polished up on Typescript and React and enjoyed how I could bring into practice in my project without excuses (dirty legacy code..). With a classmate, I solved a <a href="https://github.com/elchead/mars-kata" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">small kata</a> to practice TDD and get to know Svelte. It was really fun but also instructive to see the others perspective.
I also developed a little <a href="https://github.com/elchead/blog-cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">blog CLI</a> which is super useful to me and forked a personal CRM to my needs.</p>
<p>Reserving time for my learning goals and work on what seems meaningful to me is something I definitely plan to keep.</p>
<h2 id="swimming-and-salsa">Swimming and Salsa</h2>
<p>I found much more time to exercise and rediscovered swimming. I like how swimming calms the mind and brings the focus to the body. Compared to other sports, I find it easier to do deliberate practice: focusing on breathing, body movements. And observing the improvement always felt rewarding. I went from panting after about 50m to calmly swimming freestyle for more than 1km.</p>
<p>I also went outside to dance much more often. I took my first bachata course and went on a salsa congress. I made progress in my style, but I realized that I need a regular dancing partner to practice outside classes. Consolidating new figuras in memory takes more than one class, but unless I feel good about them I won&rsquo;t incorporate them into social dance. As a salsa master told me on one occasion: &ldquo;It takes a lot of practice and going through the basics gets repetitive and boring, but this is what it takes to get good.&rdquo; I want to keep Salsa as a fun activity and don&rsquo;t become professional, but I will need more deliberate practice to progress.</p>
<h2 id="heading">☀️🏝😀</h2>
<p>The sunny weather and secondly the beach were real boosters for my happiness that I don&rsquo;t want to miss anymore. Sometimes I would pause and just appreciate how good it is to be here in this moment compared to the grey winter in Germany. The sun is my simple pleasure. Similarly, I also love the sea. I particularly enjoyed yoga classes on the beach in the morning, watching the sunrise, the outdoor beach gym and cold bathing.
But even a simple walk by the sea would lift my mood.
I&rsquo;ve set both elements high on the priority list for where I want to live after my studies.</p>
<h2 id="the-more-social-me">The more social me</h2>
<p>Since living alone during COVID times, I spent much less time socializing but also enjoyed spending time with myself. The experience with my roommates and the more social nature of the people here (talking and hanging out..), however got me to rethink.
I want to share more with my friends again and seek more time to hang out together. I&rsquo;ve changed my attitude towards strangers and enjoy talking to new people. In the last weeks that I approached people, I was impressed by the positive responses and amazed by the kind of people I coincidentally met.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The time passed all too fast and I am hesitant to leave. But what lies ahead is the next chapter enriched by all the learnings from the last one. Sure, I won&rsquo;t have another Erasmus semester but adventures are not a matter of chance or destiny, but rather something that needs to be looked for. I&rsquo;m excited to see what the next chapter will be!</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>