<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Elchead</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Elchead</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://elchead.me/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guest-article SpeedupBuddy - Questions I wish I had asked years before</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/sup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/sup/</guid><description>Photo by Pixels
Since last summer, I am part of a Mentoring program called SpeedupBuddy, targeted towards students from non-academic families. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to have found a mentor with a very good match and he has been accompanying me on an interesting journey about finding out more about myself since then. In the short article, I want to share my experience and some personal revelations I had since then.</description></item><item><title>Best of Podcasts 2020</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2021-01-12-best-of-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2021-01-12-best-of-podcasts/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>9300 minutes - According to Spotify, I spent this much time listening to podcasts last year. It was the first year where I started to prefer it consistently over listening to music. In the beginning, it was mainly for practicing Chinese (<a href="https://speakchinesenaturally.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Speak Chinese Naturally</a>, <a href="https://storyfm.cn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">GuShiFM</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCNmZr4WBw71bdJYjaycLodA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">DaPeng Speak Chinese</a>), and they helped me a lot! I still remember how I occasionally trapped myself evading from them because it was demanding, and the stories were not always very exciting. Now, this has gone away and I even listen to doze off.</p>
<p>But it was only until the second half of the year when I found them as a source of inspiration and realized how much I enjoy listening to philosophical and deeply personal conversations. I first shared the episodes of Derek Sivers and Naval Ravikant with my mentor. He was also excited by them and I really like how we now sometimes cite the episodes to explain our ideas or make a point. I would love to have more of this, so feel free to reach out if any of this also speaks to you :)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Content collection - The power of Check-Later apps</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</guid><description><![CDATA[<!-- TODO add img -->
<p>How do you consume media? - It sounds like a silly question, but I think it&rsquo;s very much worth thinking about it. After all, we spend a considerable amount of time doing it. It might be to research something specific, to learn something new, or simply to entertain ourselves. The internet provides a rich resource of information, but it&rsquo;s probably also the most distracting source.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Notion - A powerful documenting tool for Notes, Projects, Wiki...</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/notion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/notion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I feel excited to share the tool that has most influenced my exploration of a more organized me. Many people see it as an alternative to Evernote, but for me, it felt much more powerful than a note-taking app. I immediately fell in love with its simplistic markdown approach, which easily yields attractive pages. I always had difficulties keeping notes that I would like to check again, which discouraged me from using them extensively. Notion completely changed my attitude toward note-taking and writing because it made it fun - Yes, it indirectly made me write this blog!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Second Brain - My life-changing companion</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-15-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-15-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the beginning of a bigger series on which I want to introduce some ideas about my new life companion. For me, this concept was pivotal in how I want to live. It helped me become clearer on what I want and focus on my priorities. I use it to offload information to have more capacities for being present-focused. Finally, I became fully digital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I struggled quite a bit on finding a proper word because it touches so many aspects. It is related to productivity, self-improvement, and knowledge management. In the end, I think that the term second brain, made famous by Tiago Forte, is maybe a good superordinate for what it tries to achieve. In fact, I was hugely inspired by him and adopted a lot of his ideas. He describes the second-brain as a knowledge management system. Once I got into this area, I discovered a lot of other content related to productivity and self-improvement. I took what seems useful to me, and I am still exploring.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design Patterns: How to write better code</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 09:18:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-10-software_patterns/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Learning to write proper code is hard. Who doesn&rsquo;t know it, after having an initial spark on how to solve a problem, it is tentative to immediately start coding.</p>
<p>I guess most of us did so initially and almost always ended up on dead-end roads. Taking the time to think a design through before writing the first line is indispensable for larger projects but even makes things easier for smaller undertakings.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-06-introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 09:18:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-06-introduction/</guid><description><![CDATA[Congratulations on being one of the first visitors to this new blog.
If any topic speaks to you, I&rsquo;d be happy to get in touch and hear about your thoughts and suggestions!
I&rsquo;ve planned to post stuff concerning the following topics:
 Programming Learning Chinese Productivity  Stay tuned!
Quick intro I&rsquo;m Adrian, currently pursuing a Master&rsquo;s degree in Computational Science &amp; Engineering at TU Munich. Besides my newly discovered passion for programming, I&rsquo;ve been an enthusiastic language learner since my early teenage-times.]]></description></item></channel></rss>