<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unix cheatsheet - Beyond the basics</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</guid><description>We developers use the terminal a lot and there are a lot of tricks that can ease our work. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking beyond the essentials of getting stuff done in the shell! The quickest way to find what you need is probably to use tldr. But the frequently used hacks are best learned once to know about all the good stuff and work effectively. I recently found the great The Linux Command Handbook from Freecodecamp and went over it to extract the useful bites that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Fixing CSV parsing - First attribute not regonized (BOM)</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</guid><description>Today, I wanted to read a CSV file from Notion and stumbled on the issue that my first attribute was not properly read. I validated my code on a another file before, but on this file it just didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Turns out that I had the same issue with another npm library. What bothered me was that when printing the object, I could see the attribute, but it had single quotes around it and was printed in green.</description></item><item><title>Mental Models - How they contribute to a happy life</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/mental-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/mental-models/</guid><description>Mental models are how we see and interpret the world. In reality, nothing has meaning, the world is just full of events obeying the laws of the universe. These laws constrain how we live: time is finite and irreversible, gravity puts us on the ground, physical needs ensure survial, etc. But beyond that everything is really up to our minds. We are all born within this frame, but over time we all have different experiences.</description></item><item><title>CKAD preparation - Tips for the Kubernetes exam</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</guid><description>Recently, I took the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exam and would like to share some tips for the preparation. Be aware that at the end of September, an updated 2021 version will be released, so contents will change a bit. Nevertheless, the exam contains 20 questions that need to be completed in 2 hours. So its crucial to be quick and comfortable with the kubectl CLI and formatting yaml files. But first things first:</description></item><item><title>Smart file organization - How PARA works for me after 8 months</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/para/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/para/</guid><description>More than half a year ago, I started building my second brain - an intent to store information digitally to offload it from your brain. Organization and structure are crucial for this system to work, even more than content collection. I can tell from past experience of dead archives that I had long forgotten about their existence. But even worse, file corpses can make it harder to find what we want.</description></item><item><title>VIM - Why geeks love it and you will too</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/vim/</guid><description><![CDATA[VIM is more than just a text editor for geeks and the cool kids! If you aren&rsquo;t convinced or haven&rsquo;t heard about it - stick with me to see how it&rsquo;s magic might also improve your typing experience.
Also, VIM is absolutely worth learning if you don&rsquo;t intend to use the terminal program! Because of its vibrant community, VIM features are also supported in popular IDEs like Visual Studio Code (the best of both worlds imho) or even your Browser.]]></description></item><item><title>Guest-article SpeedupBuddy - Questions I wish I had asked years before</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/sup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/sup/</guid><description>Photo by Pixels
Since last summer, I am part of a Mentoring program called SpeedupBuddy, targeted towards students from non-academic families. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to have found a mentor with a very good match and he has been accompanying me on an interesting journey about finding out more about myself since then. In the short article, I want to share my experience and some personal revelations I had since then.</description></item><item><title>Best of Podcasts 2020</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/2021-01-12-best-of-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/2021-01-12-best-of-podcasts/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>9300 minutes - According to Spotify, I spent this much time listening to podcasts last year. It was the first year where I started to prefer it consistently over listening to music. In the beginning, it was mainly for practicing Chinese (<a href="https://speakchinesenaturally.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Speak Chinese Naturally</a>, <a href="https://storyfm.cn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">GuShiFM</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCNmZr4WBw71bdJYjaycLodA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">DaPeng Speak Chinese</a>), and they helped me a lot! I still remember how I occasionally trapped myself evading from them because it was demanding, and the stories were not always very exciting. Now, this has gone away and I even listen to doze off.</p>
<p>But it was only until the second half of the year when I found them as a source of inspiration and realized how much I enjoy listening to philosophical and deeply personal conversations. I first shared the episodes of Derek Sivers and Naval Ravikant with my mentor. He was also excited by them and I really like how we now sometimes cite the episodes to explain our ideas or make a point. I would love to have more of this, so feel free to reach out if any of this also speaks to you :)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Content collection - The power of Check-Later apps</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</guid><description><![CDATA[<!-- TODO add img -->
<p>How do you consume media? - It sounds like a silly question, but I think it&rsquo;s very much worth thinking about it. After all, we spend a considerable amount of time doing it. It might be to research something specific, to learn something new, or simply to entertain ourselves. The internet provides a rich resource of information, but it&rsquo;s probably also the most distracting source.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Notion - A powerful documenting tool for Notes, Projects, Wiki...</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/notion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/notion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I feel excited to share the tool that has most influenced my exploration of a more organized me. Many people see it as an alternative to Evernote, but for me, it felt much more powerful than a note-taking app. I immediately fell in love with its simplistic markdown approach, which easily yields attractive pages. I always had difficulties keeping notes that I would like to check again, which discouraged me from using them extensively. Notion completely changed my attitude toward note-taking and writing because it made it fun - Yes, it indirectly made me write this blog!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>