<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Letters on Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/</link><description>Recent content in Letters on Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Not looking away</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/not-looking-away/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/not-looking-away/</guid><description>I used to take the path of least resistance in society. I rarely disagree, because I would not change their beliefs and just cause conflicts. In delicate situations, I would almost never speak up and help someone in public.
Let me be concrete. Last week, a drunk / drugged man, who did not wear a mask, was continously coughing on the metro. He did not even use the crook of his arm against the germ spreading.</description></item><item><title>Joy of missing out</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/jomo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/jomo/</guid><description>As I am writing this, I am sitting in the garden on a weekend without any plans to go out. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to miss out on all the events and parties that are happening in Berlin right now.
Joy of missing out means relishing to stay in, enjoying your own company, and getting to work on your own projects
&amp;ndash; Nesslabs - Jomo
Why? Because I&amp;rsquo;m an introvert. I refuel energy by being alone.</description></item><item><title>Finding mental peace with planning</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/mental-peace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/mental-peace/</guid><description>When giving a todo planner to my friends birthday the other day, I was asked if I am super organized and into this &amp;ldquo;GTD&amp;rdquo; (Getting Things Done) thing. After affirming it, we talked about how it helps to get all thoughts out of the mind, because everything is captured in the system. Whenever, I think of a question, a gift idea, something I want do or commit to do, I track it.</description></item><item><title>Thinking out loud</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/thinking-out-loud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/thinking-out-loud/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not used to talking about feelings and raw thoughts. It&amp;rsquo;s how I grew up and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to undo. Feelings make you vulnerable and I saw them as a burden to others. So I mostly kept them to myself. I found ways to process them: by studying, listening to music, exercising and sleeping. Basically, disengaging from my feelings and letting time heal everything. Time alleviates strong emotions. But I think that this evasive way also disconnects myself from people.</description></item></channel></rss>