<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Thoughts - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://adrianstobbe.com/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Thoughts - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adrianstobbe.com/categories/thoughts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Challenging the shortsighted me</title><link>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/shortsighted-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/shortsighted-me/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Resisting impulses is hard. We all have such impulses:
like mindlessly scrolling social media in the morning, eating junk food, or too many coffee-breaks at work. They can be manifold, but they are so enticing in the moment, because they temptate us with immediate pleasure or stress release.
It&rsquo;s when our primitive, short-term thinking mind tries to get control. In the book &ldquo;Thinking Fast and Slow&rdquo;, Daniel Kahneman describes two modes of thinking:</p>
<ul>
<li>“System 1” = The instant, unconscious, automatic, intuitive thinking.</li>
<li>“System 2” = The slower, conscious, rational, deliberate thinking.</li>
</ul>
<p>The primitive impulses come from System 1 and when we don&rsquo;t deliberately observe ourselves, we follow them.
In short: System 1 is the default, System 2 needs attention.</p>
<h2 id="system-1-in-action">System 1 in action</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s System 1, when I come home late exhausted from the day and give in to an eating crave. System 2 knows it&rsquo;s bad, but when my energy is low, it becomes hard to think; hard to resist.
It&rsquo;s also System 1 that tempts me to eat 5 pieces of cake, although System 2 knows that I won&rsquo;t feel good afterwards.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s System 1, that when getting my phone to find something, urges me to check for new messages.
System 2 knows it&rsquo;s bad, because I become distracted, sometimes agitated, and forget what I wanted to do.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also System 1, that entertains itself with daydreaming or grooving to music while doing boring, mundane activities such as packing things. System 1 works well, when it&rsquo;s habitual, when we don&rsquo;t need to think. But slight deviations, such as things not being in the exact same place or something additional that needs to be thought, let the system fail.</p>
<h2 id="dealing-with-impulses">Dealing with impulses</h2>
<h3 id="save-energy-with-routines">Save energy with routines</h3>
<p>Always being in System 2 mode is too expensive and we wouldn&rsquo;t get things done. Willpower is limited.
So it&rsquo;s crucial to focus System 2 on the important. Routines help to take the burden of System 2, so it pays off to routinize reoccurring problems.<br>
If I make it a rule to brush my teeth, when I get foot in the door late, it makes it a bit easier to resist the food craving.
When I turn off notifications or use my laptop instead of the phone, it becomes easier to avoid distraction.</p>
<h3 id="mastering-self-control">Mastering Self-control</h3>
<p>Fortunately, our lifes are not just montonous routines. Many situations are unexpected and our feelings vary.
The reason we keep doing harmful things is that our System 2 is not sharply observing or is lacking will power to tame System 1.
The first step is to step out of automatic mode and shift the focus to the present. Meditation is good practice for this. By shifting the focus on the breath and not doing anything else, it becomes easier to observe the mind.</p>
<p>After becoming aware of our impulses, the challenge is to substitute something immediately rewarding against some more far-distant and currently non-tangible benefit.
The problem is that our lazy-self seeks to maximize present reward.</p>
<p>But how do we work against our lazy pleasuring seeking self to pursue something that pays off long term?</p>
<p>Here comes the power of self-control. Learning to resist, to say no. The key to build positive habits is self-control. Saying no is much more important than saying yes.
Saying yes is easy, it&rsquo;s indulging, gives immediate rewards and avoids problems (in the very moment).
Saying no is uncomfortable. Be it external like turning down an invitation or ask for help, or internal like resisting an urge to eat junk food. Most often we / our System 2 knows we should say no, but we lack self-control.
We forego the long-term reward of sticking to our high priorities to avoid imminent pain and discomfort. Even if the pain will be much higher in the future.</p>
<p>But saying &ldquo;No&rdquo; can be pleasing. Every time we say it, it&rsquo;s a proof of strength, self-determination, and a clear and focused mind. Isn&rsquo;t this a nice compliment to yourself?
Exercise feels rewarding after overcoming the inertia to go and pushing the body to it&rsquo;s limits. Work is rewarding after solving a hard, frustrating problem.
We constantly pursue comfort in all aspects of life, but comfort is not fullfilling, it&rsquo;s not rewarding.
We should instead associate discomfort; that is saying no with rewards.</p>
<p>Self-control unlocks positive change by letting us focus on the important, but more importantly by steering us away from the harmful. And like everything else, we can practice it. So I invite you to find your impulses in your day. Find small things, such as not checking the phone, or not eating the first time you feel the urge. <a href="https://podcastnotes.org/huberman-lab/optimize-your-brain-with-science-based-tools-huberman-lab/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Dr. Huberman</a> coins these NO-GO&rsquo;s and tries to find 15 small NO-GO&rsquo;s every day. But it&rsquo;s better to start small than not at all. My big NO-GO are sweets this month.
What&rsquo;s yours?</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>2022 - Goals</title><link>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/2022/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><style>
  #callout {
    background: #ececec;
     

    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
      padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
</style>

<div id="callout">
  <div></div>
  <div id="callout-inner">TLDR, the short version is at the end :) </div>
</div>

I hope you had a good start in the new year! I&rsquo;m late in the game, but I want to share my goals for this year with you.</p>
<p>I started with it last year and I found them helpful to focus my energy and time. Every week, I checked my progress in my weekly review.
All in all, I am satisfied because I reached the important goals and learnt more about my capacity. Most of my goals were habit building ones like: meditate daily, do exercise bidaily, go to bed before 10:30 pm, journal daily, read 10 books.. But there is still much to be improved upon. I defined too many goals and did not did not prioritize accordingly. Also, I want to remind myself more often of them, so I will make a pinned note on my desktop and phone (thanks to <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/2021-goals/#looking-back-at-2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">thesephist</a> for the idea).</p>
<p>So here are my goals for this year:</p>
<h2 id="goals">Goals</h2>
<h3 id="long-term-learning">Long-term learning</h3>
<p>The idea of the learning projects arose last year through a friend who reserved one hour in the morning to read books for his long-term career development. In the past, I easily got caught up with what is important in the moment and invested all effort into it. But I became a believer of the 80/20 rule and want to invest not only in the urgent but also in the important (Eisenhower matrix).</p>
<p>I want to take time in the morning to learn what I believe important and listen more to technical podcasts. I already discovered a lot of tools and resources through it last year: Learning Golang with TDD (my fav), Wails, Svelte, vim tricks&hellip; And it broadens my horizon on topics I&rsquo;ve never heard about like BPFs for Observability of microservices and compiler development in the old days..
So exposing myself to new input is one part and the second is to get my own hands dirty to really learn. This can mean solving exercises / following a learning project or applying the new tool / language in my own little project.</p>
<h3 id="connect-with-friends-and-be-a-host">Connect with friends and be a host</h3>
<p>I found the hosting goal on <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/2021-goals/#looking-back-at-2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">thesephist&rsquo;s list</a> and my immediate reaction was that I want to do it too.</p>
<p>I love to get to know new people and exchange on interests. Jordan Harbinger got me intrigued with his Networking course !! to be more intentional about network building. It happened only a few times to me until now, but it&rsquo;s gratifying to help a friend through some connection. But while calls are great to exchange on technical stuff, it&rsquo;s not the same as hanging out with a friend. I guess I&rsquo;m not the exception, but I just connect much better with people emotionally in person. Unfortunately, many of my friends live in other cities or even countries. In the past, I did not make enough effort to visit because I mistook digitally staying in touch to be enough.
This year, I plan to visit more close but far-away friends.
But getting back to the intro, I also want to host gatherings with friends to connect and make space for good conversations. I was very humble to keep the number to two, because of my current living situation (not having an own home + switching places) but for me it&rsquo;s most important to start doing it at all.
I like to be proactive and I want to learn to become a good host.
This also applies to technical activities. Last year, I started the clean-code challenge with a friend, invited a friend to solve a coding kata together, initiated to go on a hackathon with some friends, but I want to grow these activities in size and quantity.</p>
<h3 id="exploring-fun-skills">Exploring fun skills</h3>
<p>As part of my goal to socialize more, I want to bring more fun to conversations. Being a good listener, asking curious questions is all great, but I want to be more dynamic in groups. However, most of my hobbies are not fun to show (writing, meditation, swimming&hellip;). Last year, I found <a href="/books/storyworthy/" rel="">storytelling</a>, re-read <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35167685-surely-you-re-joking-mr-feynman" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">&ldquo;Surely You&rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!&rdquo;</a> (highly recommended) and got inspired to be more curious in exploring random interests. In the case of Feynman it was opening locks, solving puzzles, playing tricks, very random observations that challenged his friends to conduct a fun experiment.. Yeah, he was an intriguing guy..</p>
<p>This year, I want to explore two random interests. Candidates are storytelling (e.g. join toastmasters..), learning magic tricks, learning the ukulele..</p>
<h3 id="engage-with-the-twitter-community">Engage with the twitter community</h3>
<p>Last year, I made it my goal to join twitter and try it out. Indeed, I found some great people to follow and want to engage more in threads and discussions. Also, I want to use it to share my findings and micro-thoughts.
If you are a twitter user and I don&rsquo;t yet follow you, please let me know :)
My bigger goal of this is to build friendships and a community with shared interests.</p>
<h3 id="mostly-vegan-and-sweet-free-month">Mostly vegan and sweet free month</h3>
<p>Through living with my vegan roommates, I got more aware about the origin of dairy products. I already rarely ate meat before, but through my roommates I explored delicious vegan meals and saw that I can largely avoid dairies as well. I reduced my meat consumption close to zero, but I hadn&rsquo;t given up on fish. I&rsquo;m not yet ready or convinced for going completely vegan, but I want to make my diet at least 80% vegan. I believe in it&rsquo;s health benefits and want to greatly reduce my footprint in the animal industry.<br>
Secondly, I want to exercise self-control and remind myself of the addiction to sugar.
My Christmas sweets (gone within a few days) have reminded me of it and how they often makes me feel unwell. I will resist sweets for one month this year and keep sugar to a minimum throughout the rest of the year.</p>
<h2 id="tldr">TLDR</h2>
<p>




</p>
<h3 id="habits-i-want-to-build--fortify">Habits I want to build / fortify</h3>
<ul>
<li>No distractions during first 3h of day (phone)</li>
<li>Learning hour in the morning</li>
<li>Journal daily</li>
<li>Care for mental well-being daily (meditation, walks&hellip;)</li>
</ul>]]></description></item><item><title>My fuckups of 2021</title><link>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/fuckups-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/fuckups-2021/</guid><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The only real mistake is the one from which we learn nothing - Henry Ford.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In 2021, I took more time to reflect on my failures. While doing my yearly review, I decided to pick 3 fuckups and share them with you. Maybe it can help you, avoid similar mistakes. And if not, may my naiveness at least make you laugh!</p>
<h2 id="the-macbook-that-proved-light-as-air">The MacBook that proved light as air</h2>
<p>Earlier this year, I bought a used MacBook Air. I fucked up in nearly all possible ways and it taught me many lessons.</p>
<p>First, I bought it on eBay Kleinanzeigen from a nice guy who even gave me a discount as a student and I had a nice chat with him when picking it up. He quickly showed me that it was working (turned it on) and I blindly believed that everything would be good; that is what the description said and the guy was trustworthy!
When at home, I quickly found out that the battery had a defect. I don&rsquo;t think that the owner mischievously lied to me, because after some discussions he later generously agreed to give a discount or help with repair.
But it was my responsibility to make a careful check (battery, display, keyboard, touchpad, internet, ports).</p>
<p>A few weeks later on a windy day, I went outside to study and opened it on a table. For one second I did not hold it and the next moment my beautiful MacBook Air flew through the air. It was a quick gust and after a few meters it crashed on the rough floor.
I already expected the worst, but it was still fully working. Nevertheless, but it got some ugly scratches and deformations. How was I so mindless not putting one and one together on such a windy day?</p>
<p>This is not yet the end. Later, I decided to buy a cheap battery on eBay to replace it together with my dad. Paying Apple 140 Euros for the repair just seemed like a big rip-off to me!
The replacement was quite fiddly and when connecting the new battery, the CPU suddenly got hot and it started smoking. My dad even got a slight burn. Now, the MacBook was completely dead. How could this have gone much worse?</p>
<p>The moral of the story is to be more averse of big risks. A big second-hand purchase should be carefully checked. People might not have bad intents, but I am responsible for everything that might be discovered afterwards. Secondly, it&rsquo;s not worth to risk a big loss to save a few bucks because it might turn out much more expensive.</p>
<h2 id="missed-chances-during-my-erasmus-exchange">Missed chances during my Erasmus exchange</h2>
<p>When coming to Barcelona, I was determined to avoid the international bubble. I had been seeing it during my stay in China and I largely avoided it, because I wanted the &ldquo;China experience&rdquo;. I&rsquo;d say I succeeded because I tried to hang out with Chinese whenever possible, but nevertheless most of my friends were internationals. However, I somehow failed to transfer this observation to my next exchange. I took the wrong conclusion from the observation that it is easier to connect with Spanish people because we are culturally closer.</p>
<p>The first day I arrived on the campus in Barcelona, I ignored the compatriots behind my back that were getting to know each other. I ignored all Erasmus welcoming activities, because I wanted to make Spanish friends. And while I was disappointed to see that there was no canteen to talk to new faces during lunch, I still believed that there would be plenty of opportunities through uni associations, sports, classes, parties.
As it turned out though, the activities at my uni were very counted (or I missed the secret channel ^^). Dancing was another prospect, but in the end I could count the total number of peers with my fingers.
I also made a few intents approaching people on campus, but of course they mostly spoke Catalan. I did not expect it, but it made me feel a bit like an outsider. I guess it taught me that I would not want to live in a place whose local language I would not speak (or plan to learn).
I regret not having participated at the welcoming events. I learnt that I need to seize opportunities in the moment, to not bet on later chances because they might not come. It was a missed chance with not much to lose.</p>
<h2 id="chasing-rainbows-or-the-spanish-drivers-license">Chasing rainbows or the Spanish drivers license</h2>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t take driving classes like all my friends at 17, because I didn&rsquo;t want a car and thought there would come a better moment to do it abroad cheaply.
Short disclaimer: that was a stupid thought. Last year,I was finally abroad and not so much loaded with uni and work. Besides it would be cheaper here in Spain - perfect timing. But my first mistake was not to inform well on the local circumstances. I knew I would need a NIE document and even checked the official website, but it just said no appointments available at the moment. I thought: &ldquo;oh well COVID&rdquo;, it will hopefully change when I am there and there will be a way.. After quite some effort to get an officer on the phone, I found out that this is the default display because the few new appointments are immediately snatched away. For weeks I tried to get an appointment by constantly refreshing the page, booked one in a far away city, but all in vain. It was hopeless. I finally got one through a bot from a dude on Github - that&rsquo;s how insane the situation is. <a href="https://twitter.com/astobbe_/status/1448710106875629574" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Paying the NIE fee</a> was a whole different story.. Before, I went to many driving schools to ask for the required documents and all replied that I&rsquo;d be fine with the NIE. Long story short, it was unrealistic to complete it in Barcelona and after finding a school in another city they found out that I&rsquo;d need to proof 6 months of residency in Spain. After all the efforts, it failed on this.</p>
<p>Had I done my research early (to my defense, it was not pointed out on all websites) or contacted the authorities directly, I could have saved all this wasted time. My takeaway: Get the information early, before investing much effort. Otherwise you are irrationally inclined to pursue it no matter the cost. Secondly, get information either directly from the source (authorities) or google experiences from others. I received much misinformation from the driving schools and even banks..</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Mental Models - How they contribute to a happy life</title><link>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/mental-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://adrianstobbe.com/posts/mental-models/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Mental models are how we see and interpret the world. In reality, nothing has meaning, the world is just full of events obeying the laws of the universe.
These laws constrain how we live: time is finite and irreversible, gravity puts us on the ground, physical needs ensure survial, etc. But beyond that everything is really up to our minds. We are all born within this frame, but over time we all have different experiences. More importantly, those experiences shape how we interpret and understand the world. While growing up, we see how our characters and mindsets diverge from those that were so similar to us back in the early school days. Once we leave our home to explore other cultures we see the diversity of lifestyles. What unites us is the desire to have a happy life. What differentiate us is the intepretation of how to attain it.</p>
<h3 id="the-complexity-of-life">The complexity of life</h3>
<p>Interestingly, not even religion, a centerpiece in most cultures, seems to provide an answer to that question. They provide guidance in how not to live (think Ten Commandments and their analogues in other religions) based on core values that are shared in the community and often a common belief in some kind of higher sanctitity.
Religion is a powerful mental model on how to see the world, but even it is only a part of our identity.
Just look to see how different the lifestyle of an ostentatious Sheik in Dubai is to that of the geographically close average co-religionist in Iran.
The living-circumstances are totally different of course, but how they choose to live is driven by values.
After all, there are frugal millionaires who stick to a modest lifestyle (take <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ronald_Read_%28philanthropist%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Ronald Read</a>)!</p>
<p>Maybe a more common denominator of lifestyle is to be found among those who share a life philosophy (Stoicism, Epicureanism, Hedonism&hellip;). A life philosophy is yet another mental model which lays out values to be lived by.</p>
<h3 id="values">Values</h3>
<p>Regardless of our convictions, we all have values - even though some are more intentional and proactive in defining them than others. I guess many people choose to live by their values &ldquo;intuitively&rdquo; - they do what feels good or right. This includes myself until I came to adapt new mental models on how I want to live.</p>
<h3 id="life-areas-as-daily-guidance">Life areas as daily guidance</h3>
<p>In defining what matters to me, I found it helpful to become aware of my different life areas and realize them as something that needs maintenance.
It takes effort to maintain the standard I define for myself, so I reserve time and energy for it: Family matters to me? Do I regularly take time to call my grandparents? My friends birthday is approaching, so do I reserve time to think about how to surprise her?
I want to become financially independent? Do I review my spendings and allocate enough savings to long term investments? Do I review my portfolio to reallocate according to my risk and diversify enough?
I want to live healthy? So, I reserve time to go to the gym and explore new healthy recipes.</p>
<p>My life areas include: professional ones like my job, university and coding, in which I want to learn new skills and apply them to side projects.
My leisure areas include: reading, my blog, language learning, finance, health (exercise, meditation) and exploration. The last one I defined for myself lately with the desire to try out more new things. It includes planning adventures, travels, etc., but also learning completely new skills in a short time. The latter is inspired by the monthly <a href="https://learn.uno/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Learning challenge</a>.
When planning for the week, I view it through the lens of my life areas.
Of course, I still engage in spontaneous activities, but most of my time is dedicated to maintain and develop my life areas.</p>
<h3 id="hell-yeah-or-no">Hell Yeah Or No</h3>
<p>Another helpful model to decide my time commitments is: <a href="https://sive.rs/n" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Hell Yeah or No</a>.
The elapse of time is governed by the law of entropy, but our perspective on time is subjective. You can either see it as a free resource to spend until its depleted or view it as a scarcity you are hesitant to spend - spending it on this means I won&rsquo;t have it for that.
I choose to view time as scarcity. I rather say no to most things to have the capacity for the &ldquo;Hell Yeah, I want to do that&rdquo; moments.
When people invite me to hang out together, the easy and default answer is yes. It will be fun and I get to know new people.
But unless, the girl I&rsquo;ve been chasing is there or the potential investor of my startup idea is there, the cost of foregoing my other committed priorities might be higher.
We do this cost-benefit analysis naturally with money, but somehow it does not seem to be the default for time.</p>
<h3 id="the-final-step">The final step</h3>
<p>Once you know your life areas and view time as scarcity, you have a good guidance on what to do, and more importantly, what not to do (saying no is more difficult!).
However, there is still one more crucial step missing. We might decide to build that new cool app, or organize that crazy suprise party, but these are big projects that can be intimidating. Much anxiety and procrastination comes from not having clear what to do next. And this even applies to much smaller undertakings such as writing an article.
I find it helpful to view every undertaking that takes me more than a couple of minutes as a project (for more check <a href="https://gettingthingsdone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Getting Things Done</a>). The big projects then needs to be broken up into actionable items. In fact, its even enough to define the next tiny step toward progress.
The first step for the surprise party might be calling a friend to ask for help or brainstorming ideas.
At this point you have translated the abstract life area concept into a concrete action.
If you plan your days with actionable items, you know exactly what to do and can stay away from external distractions.
This gives you a sense of control over your life - you are the steersman with a clear heading, robust to the roaring sea.
And other than money or fame, the feeling of control seems to be the univeral fuel of happiness:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>More than your salary. More than the size of your house. More than the prestige of your job. Control over doing what you want, when you want to, with the people you want to, is the broadest lifestyle variable that makes people happy.
&ndash; <cite>The Psychology of Money, Morgan Housel</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="you-want-more">You want more?</h3>
<p>These thoughts are my intepretation and takeaways from a lot of books and blog posts I read (and of course reflections). I could not fit them all into this all ready long article, but I&rsquo;m considering to do a follow up article. For now, I want to leave you with some recommendations. My book notes are also linked.</p>
<p>I shortly alluded to the value of a life philosphy, and this book on Stoicisim was very impactful on me: <a href="/books/stoic-joy/" rel="">A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy - William B. Irvine</a></p>
<p>The name speaks for itself, one of my favourite authors:
<a href="/books/hell-yeah/" rel="">Hell Yeah or No</a></p>
<div id="reachout-callout">
    <div>💙</div>
      <div id="callout-inner">
      If you made it until here, I&#39;d like to thank you for reading! Yeah, time is precious.. In case you think I got something wrong, want to recommend a book or share your thoughts, I&#39;d highly appreciate that!
      You can reach me through <a href='mailto:stobbe.adrian@gmail.com'>Email</a> or <a href='https://twitter.com/astobbe_'>Twitter</a>
    </div>
  </div>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>