<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Letters - Category - Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/categories/letters/</link><description>Letters - Category - Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/categories/letters/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Love and Feel</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/love-and-feel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/love-and-feel/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I stepped out of my journal routine lately and with it lost the grip on my steering wheel. I let myself go with the current.
It felt great to let go, relax and just enjoy a few days. It felt so human to just be and focus on being with people. I found a new motto, which is not really new to me yet I never had it so present and felt so strongly about it before:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To live is to love. To live is to feel.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It means many things to me. It&rsquo;s a form of saying carpe diem - to enjoy the moment. To love myself, what I am doing, my weaknesses and flaws. To be aware about my feelings, appreciate and express them. It&rsquo;s also how I see relationships. By spending a few days among girlies I also shifted my ideal of friendship toward it. Meaningful friendships are formed by a genuine interest to get to know each other deeply, by showing care and safety to express whatever is on your mind. Friendships are about sharing feelings - yes, this also applies to boys! My guy friendships all lack on this. I have the impression that girls have deeper connection and understanding for this reason. Nevertheless I also appreciate the side of my male friends, since all this emotion stuff can also get quite heavy.. ;)</p>
<p>Another epiphany was to realize the importance of emotions even outside of friendships. Emotions make us human and they catch our interest. Think about it. All types of entertainment: movies, shows, music are aimed to talk to our emotions. Hardly anything dull speaks to us. A great idea or insight can be exciting, but when something is dull you will probably lose focus and interest way before you might find an insight.</p>
<p>Days ago, I enjoyed a great talk on building a blockchain. It was a difficult topic and a bit too fast paced. Yet the talk was so fun. I wondered what it was and realized the key was the speakers liveliness. He was attentive about the audience, encouraged questions, had a very chill and casual speaking style, dropped some humor here and there and gave lively examples. He was very confident and yet humble and kind. 
Besides, attracting our attention emotions also play an important role in forming strong memories, yes also learning.
My point is that sharpening awareness of your own and others feelings is immensely helpful even when the matter is evidently not about emotions.</p>
<p>The role of feelings also made me come to another realization. I used to be very purpose driven. All I did ought to serve a purpose: get work done, develop skills, learn something new, maintain health, show gratitude..</p>
<p>But not everything needs an objective. I should not feel the need for a purpose to call my parents or to connect with a friend. The body is not designed to always work and &ldquo;be productive&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s good to remind myself that a fulfilled life is one balanced with objective meaning (work, skills) and emotional meaning (love, friends, humor, fun activities). I want to be more aware to connect emotionally: Show love, to observe and understand their feelings, to get to know yourself better. Be playful by saying something bold and unconventional. Act foolish once in a while. Play with your tone. Show emotions. If you are excited, show it. If you are disappointed, in grieve, show it. But being emotionless is unattractive. Be anything but boring.</p>
<p>So this is my new maxim to live by. Yet putting it into practice is hard and I asked myself what is hindering me. At times, I am already living up to my ideals.
Through stoicism I got more appreciate about life. I have deepened some of my friendships. At times, I show affection with my family and am engaged and curious to understand and learn about them. Sometimes, I give compliments and show gratitude. Sometimes, I am enthusiastic, courageous and not afraid to make a fool of myself.</p>
<p>But at other times I am thoughtless and feel disconnected. I realize that this happens when I struggle with my emotions and have too many things in my head. This would also explain why meditation and time alone are so helpful. I see that working drains my energy and isolates me from the world. Why? It requires focus, i.e. it suppresses my emotions and always leaves me with open problems. This closed loop of never being done might make me feel overwhelmed. The solution? I hope that awareness helps to step out of this state and to make myself take time to refill energy through meditation and exercise.</p>
<p>I am also highly sensitive to information in that it stirs up my mind and prevents me from focus and being present. My protective measures are to put my phone away and get time in the morning to just think for myself without any input or stimuli. Meditation is also great to reset the mind but nothing is better than sleep.
I need this thinking time to set my intentions for the day.</p>
<p>Whenever I have distracting thoughts or stirred up emotions that I do not talk about, I get into safe mode. I act conventional, don&rsquo;t take much space, am nice and mostly a listener. Safe mode was the default for most of my childhood so it&rsquo;s hard to unlearn. In this mode I was accepted by almost everyone and never got into trouble. But it also prevented deep connection. The bad thing about safe mode is that it is undirected. It is really just comfort for the moment.</p>
<p>Comfort for more than a moment is bad because it compromises higher priorities. All of value in life is hard and takes effort. So I challenge myself to fully live up to my new motto.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Exploring my childhood distortions</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/childhood/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/childhood/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I avoid thinking of my past, I rather look forward. I am avoidant, because I believe I did not spent my time well. My past feels empty, when I hear other people talking about their childhood.
I also don&rsquo;t remember so much. What was I thinking, what were my dreams when I was 10? I don&rsquo;t really know. I have a hard time accessing old memories. Photos are a key to unlock them, specific questions can trigger them. But they are deeply hidden behind my preconceived, negative notion of my childhood.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GFKzE52XRmw&amp;ab_channel=TheSchoolofLife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">A video from the School of Life</a> made me question my view.
Childhood shapes how we see the world. It shapes how we feel about relationships, work, love, self-esteem, strangers, friends, happiness and so much more.
Over time we acquire expectations and patterns from these experiences and it becomes hard to change.
Since our early experiences are mostly limited to a very small environment, mostly our parents, we however have a very isolated view on the world and likely get a partially wrong understanding of what is normal.
The School of life phrases these departures from reality as distortions.
Motivated to find my childhood distortions, I took some time today in the morning to dig deeper into my memories - to explore how my young life shaped me.</p>
<p>I was suprised how I could connect to the past by just sitting alone in the sun and thinking without distractions. I surfaced how I got to be conforming, passive at times,introverted and my distortion of friendships.</p>
<p>I got to relish memories of my short but great time at my first secondary school. I laughed so much and fooled around with my old friend Nico. I remembered my old teacher. Being a teacher was more than just making us learn the school curriculum to her. She was full of love and dedicated to make us feel like a big family. Yet I changed schools after moving away to the outskirts of Berlin. I remember that it was a tough choice for me. On my last day, our social pedagogue took me to the side and reflected with me on the time we spent as class together and asked how I was feeling. I got very emotional and I believe to remember how besides my two best friends, Natalie and Lena (pardon, if I got your name wrong :/) hugged me and weeped tears when saying farewell.
On my way home that day, I was super sad and was sure to come back to see them again. Yet I never went back. Why?
I thought of going back several times afterwards. On the first opportunity, a free day in my federal state, I did not go. My mom discouraged me, because she suggested to let go and focus on my new friendships. It&rsquo;s not fair to only blame her, in the end I was probably also a bit lazy and anxious about how it might me. Time passed and I still thought about it in several occasions, but I was too ashamed already for not coming back earlier and eventually gave up.
I regret this a lot today. I reached out to my old class today, after more than 10 years. It might be too late, but I can&rsquo;t turn back time.</p>
<p>My mom convinced me to change schools to find friends at my new home and how I could fullfill my dream to learn Spanish at the new school.
Today I would have made my decision differently. I can see know that my mom just did not put much importance on relationships. That&rsquo;s why she was not supportive about keeping my old friends. She thought practically. I think my parents notion of friendship shaped mine a lot.</p>
<p>I always had friends but we never got really close. On many weekends, my parents would say why don&rsquo;t you meet with friends. I think video games had their fair share on this, but I am not sure if my introverted nature was always the reason for this or that a lack of deeper connection shaped me to desire to have time for myself today.
What do I mean by deeper connection? I almost never felt like sharing feelings or personal struggles.</p>
<p>I did not learn it at home. Talk at home was factual and unemotional. My parent&rsquo;s never had a strong dispute in front of me, they never expressed discontent. They are problem avoidant. I got to believe that showing myself vulnerable and talking about problems would come off as whiny and self-pitying. I grew thick skin and isolated in my own little world.</p>
<p>I realize that my young childhood friends were dominant to express their opionions and to talk a lot. I think this made me repress myself more and devote more energy to listenting and being nice.
A lot of people have described me as nice. Last year, someone even described me as the most polite person he got to know. I think this comes from my notion to always be nice and positive on the outside and to repress and hide the rest.
This might make a good impression on new people, but I think it was also a barrier to building emotional friendships. By not showing myself vulnerable and just presenting the good side, I maybe did not make it feel safe to share. With one friend I even got to talk about it and she confirmed that I come off a bit cold and distant.</p>
<p>I built a reputation to be the nice, obedient boy and that&rsquo;s why I kept acting like it. Being who others expect me to be. I have changed my beliefs and want to have a fluid personality today. But stepping out of my old image with people I know since many years is still a struggle.</p>
<p>I see know why I tend to be passive with old friends and in groups. Compared to other children, I spent a lot of time being with older people: my parents friends and our neighbors. I was always submissive to let them lead and talk when asked. I think it impacted me to make it my automatic response to such situations, but I know this behavior is not set in stone. In fact, my brother who went through the same became very talkative in such settings.</p>
<p>I still have many more thoughts on this, but I see this as the beginning of acknowledging and understanding my past. I have grown as a person and feel that I am living a more fullfilling and richer life today, but my childhood shaped who I am today. My superficial view made me blind to see the nice memories and how my experiences impacted me. I think this happens a lot. We form a notion and feeling about something, a much more simplified version of reality though, and then we don&rsquo;t dig deeper.
This is yet another thing we can learn from children. They don&rsquo;t yet have preconceived notions and opinions. They are genuinely curious. I want to be more of a child again and unlearn the patterns of my distortions.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>How to start good convos</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/good-convos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/good-convos/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I met some new colleagues for lunch this week and failed miserably. The others already knew each other and kept talking about that new company building in another city and contract details. So exciting, right? It was hard to step in and change topics, so I kept silent. Eventually, I asked the guy sitting opposite about his work. But he did not really seem to enjoy talking about it, so I gave up and went back to work.</p>
<p>What went wrong? They certainly did not show much interest or effort to integrate me into their group, but that&rsquo;s outside my control and I could have certainly done better than mostly staying silent.</p>
<p>My approach to good talk is usually to explore interests and look for some common ground. Out of my curiosity, I usually find something interesting and start asking questions. Actually, this is what I enjoy about talking to strangers. It&rsquo;s new territory - so much to explore (except for some boring exceptions).</p>
<p>I used to struggle how to start new conversations.
It was a real eye-opener for me to realize just how blind I am to details.
I learnt that great talkers are observant and watch for cues: the catchy T-shirt, their book, a particular behavior you share&hellip; These cues are super helpful, because they might indicate some common ground, letting you skip ahead the boring small talk right away.
Curiosity is also key. Even behind simple questions about why someone did something this way might reveal something interesting.
Recently on a friend&rsquo;s birthday, a girl asked me why I would gift a todo-planner. The others were probably just thinking: &ldquo;Oh he is german&rdquo;. We discovered that her boyfriend is also a follower of the GTD philosophy and that we share many quirks. It was great to discover this, since it&rsquo;s rare to find such people.</p>
<p>Besides asking questions, providing cues is also essential.
Only if I reveal something about myself, can the other person take cues from it and ask good questions.
This is still something I struggle with. I often only start talking when asked, but not out of own initiative.
It&rsquo;s a past behavior I need to unlearn. It&rsquo;s a good thing, as long as I don&rsquo;t go to deep into the weeds and just provide it as a cue.
I want to become more thoughtful to share something from my day. I started last year to look for storyworthy moments every day, but I still have difficulties to find that moment. To often that short great moment succumbs to the more mundane but longer lasting / more recent events.
I want to try to frame my day as a story. To capture these moments mentally as highlights of my story when they are happening and not just when asked or at the end of the day.</p>
<p>Another dimension of good conversations is humor. I admire humor in other people, but I used to believe that its just not a trait of me.
Derek Sivers description of humor made me see it in new light.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Humor means using your mind beyond necessity, beyond reality, for both noticing and imagining. It shows you quickly looked at something from many angles, found the one that amused you the most, and considerately expressed it to someone else.</p>
<p><cite>- How To Live, Derek Sivers </cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is really much something that is learnable. I don&rsquo;t want to be a comedian, but I can learn to be more observant and express things from an unusual perspective.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Not looking away</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/not-looking-away/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/not-looking-away/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I used to take the path of least resistance in society. I rarely disagree, because I would not change their beliefs and just cause conflicts. In delicate situations, I would almost never speak up and help someone in public.</p>
<p>Let me be concrete.
Last week, a drunk / drugged man, who did not wear a mask, was continously coughing on the metro. He did not even use the crook of his arm against the germ spreading. The man sitting opposite just shook his head and sighed in disbelief, but did not do anything. I was sitting next to the coughing guy, just shaking my head with the indignant opposite doing nothing. This guy was not just risking my health but also that of others.
I later thought how I could have changed something about it. The most tactful way and probably the most effective with someone drugged who doesn&rsquo;t speak my language well would have been to kindly offer a mask.
I didn&rsquo;t have a spare one this day, but now I have for cases like these. Another day on the metro, I actually observed how relieved a young lady without mask was after being offered one.</p>
<p>In other cases, like people smoking or listening to loud music it&rsquo;s more tolerable, it&rsquo;s just disturbing but not harmful. The risk of getting myself into trouble is not always worth the small benefit.
But even there I want to show more civil courage, especially with young kids.</p>
<p>I am still puzzled how to have an impact and not just sound ridiculous in many situations like kids asking me to buy cigarettes.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s about being political. I used to think that politics is just about government decisions that are largely disconnected from our individual lives. But now I believe that being political means standing up for matters whose impact is bigger than just myself.</p>
<h2 id="speak-up-and-ask-questions">Speak up and ask questions</h2>
<p>A kurdic barber told me the other day how after asking questions he got some of his muslim clients to stop their religious practice. Not by preaching, but by asking questions.
My girl told me how she changed her parents view on vegan diet from completely rejecting it as unhealthy and cult towards eating lots of vegan food. Something similar happened with another friend from a conservative family.</p>
<p>I have lots of such political situations as well, but in the past I remained silent because I thought I could not change them. Now, my goal isn&rsquo;t to change anymore. Changing someone&rsquo;s view is outside my control.
My dad might never want to eat this vegan stuff, but I can make him understand why people do it and get rid of his repugnance.
I just want speak up and express how I think. Not to preach, but to ask questions, to offer a new perspective.
That is the best I can do, this is who I want to be.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Joy of missing out</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/jomo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/jomo/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>As I am writing this, I am sitting in the garden on a weekend without any plans to go out.
I&rsquo;m happy to miss out on all the events and parties that are happening in Berlin right now.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Joy of missing out means relishing to stay in, enjoying your own company, and getting to work on your own projects</p>
<p>&ndash; <cite><a href="https://nesslabs.com/jomo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Nesslabs - Jomo</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Why? Because I&rsquo;m an introvert. I refuel energy by being alone. I get to reflect, be grateful, get new ideas, get to plan how to spend my time meaningfully with those important to me and how to express the love I feel for them.</p>
<p>I rarely suffer from FOMO, because I got to accept how limited my energy is. I know that it&rsquo;s good for me to spend lots of time alone: learning, working on projects, journaling, meditating, exercising, reading&hellip;
It makes me a more interesting person, because that&rsquo;s where I get most ideas and knowledge from.</p>
<p>Saying no to most things makes me someone who has clear values and priorities.
It reserves the energy to be good at what really matters to me.
I want to go deeper with what I already have. I still have many &ldquo;Baustellen&rdquo;: becoming more grateful, loving, mindful and disciplined.
I want to find more time for reading. I want to get better at capturing ideas and making notes. I want to express and share more of my thoughts and learning.
I want to invest in relationships. Restricting myself to only a few important people but really getting to know them.
I want to find time for learning. I don&rsquo;t find much time for learning projects at the moment. I want to get better at dancing. I want to keep practicing the ukulele consistently.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/navalbot/status/1055534617225322502?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Life is a single player game</a>.
It might sound cynical and egoistic, but I think it has a stoic truth. You need to be happy with yourself to give to others. I acknowledge that there are benevolent and giving people who put others first, but I know that I can&rsquo;t give long-term and wholeheartedly when my needs are not fullfilled. #maslows-pyramid
Anything other than yourself might be taken away at any time: friends and family, money, your belongings, your home&hellip;
When my well-being does not depend on external conditions, it&rsquo;s resilient so that I can focus on giving to others.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Finding mental peace with planning</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/mental-peace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/mental-peace/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>When giving a todo planner to my friends birthday the other day, I was asked if I am super organized and into this &ldquo;GTD&rdquo; (Getting Things Done) thing.
After affirming it, we talked about how it helps to get all thoughts out of the mind, because everything is captured in the system.
Whenever, I think of a question, a gift idea, something I want do or commit to do, I track it. Ideally I do it right after, but I am still not systematic enough in my capturing (working on it!).
My problem is that I am not yet disciplined enough to only focus on one thing and finish it before moving on. It&rsquo;s yet another reason to practice meditation - to observe thoughts and regain focus.</p>
<p>People ask why am I so meticulous about it and why I would want to be so systematic (unnatural). For one, it&rsquo;s a life philosophy to be more intentional.
I plan to stay aligned with my priorities and to ease my mind. I used to worry and think a lot about how to do things and if nothing slipped through. Now, my calendar and todo app tell me what should be done today. That&rsquo;s why I do weekly reviews and why I want to plan the next day ahead. To free my mind from organizing when I want to focus on my priorities of the day.
Does this mean that I am not spontonaeous? No, I am not rigid about plans, they are just a guide. On an unplanned day, the mind does what is comfortable in the moment. And usually it&rsquo;s the <a href="/posts/shortsighted-me/" rel="">shortsighted me</a> that wins in these instances.</p>
<p>Another thing that really drains my mental energy is decision making. Even trivial decisions such as choosing food, in what order to do things are exhausting.
As a morning person, my energy levels are high early in the day and low in the late afternoon. So the later part of the day is also when I make bad decisions. Especially if they are spontaneous.
I try to defer these decisions to a moment where I can clearly think and not feel pressured.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let “No” be the default answer. People mistakenly say yes to work, people, and places they don’t like, then need to escape to get away from their mistakes. People make bad decisions because they felt they had to decide. It would have been wiser to do nothing.</p>
<p>When someone asks you to decide, just refuse. The longer you go without deciding, the more information is revealed. Eventually, the choice is obvious and made without an agonizing decision.</p>
<p>&ndash; <cite>Derek Sivers, How To Live</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Currently, I am experimenting with a decision making blocker where I batch non-trivial decisions. In a calm moment, I then go over them. I am saying experimenting, because it&rsquo;s hard to change such fundamental things that I used to differently for so many years. I want to stack it with my journaling routine during my <a href="https://www.insider.com/tired-all-day-but-energy-before-bed-2019-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">energy peak before sleep</a>. I first heard about this peak on the <a href="https://hubermanlab.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Huberman Lab podcast</a> and want to explore more what triggers it and at what time it happens.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Ship it - My public journal</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/letters-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/letters-intro/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by <a href="https://www.jenvermet.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Jen Vermet&rsquo;s</a> ship-it and weekly letters, I will start to share my thoughts and learnings in public. I love how personal and introspective her thoughts and shared experiences are.
I&rsquo;ve started <a href="/posts/building-a-journaling-habit-with-obsidian/" rel="">journaling last year</a>, but my thoughts are mostly very raw and hidden to the outside world. By starting a public journal, I want to challenge myself to become more open and overcome the imposter that my thoughts are not worth being shared.</p>
<p>I am still figuring out the format, if it will be weekly or daily. But my goal is to share my learnings and thoughts at least once per week.</p>
<p>You will find my entries <a href="/categories/letters/" rel="">here</a>.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Thinking out loud</title><link>https://astobbe.me/letters/thinking-out-loud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/letters/thinking-out-loud/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not used to talking about feelings and raw thoughts.
It&rsquo;s how I grew up and it&rsquo;s hard to undo. Feelings make you vulnerable and I saw them as a burden to others. So I mostly kept them to myself. I found ways to process them: by studying, listening to music, exercising and sleeping. Basically, disengaging from my feelings and letting time heal everything. Time alleviates strong emotions.
But I think that this evasive way also disconnects myself from people. I blunt emotions, but don&rsquo;t solve the root cause.
It&rsquo;s because talking about feelings and problems is sensitive.
But I learnt that when <a href="/books/crucial-conversations" rel="">approached tactfully</a>, everything can be talked about. And I think there is much more to gain than to lose.
You get to know someone else’s perspective and either discover that you both felt something was wrong and want to fix it, or you find that the other does not care that much. I think even the latter is so valuable to know!</p>
<p>It actually feels so bonding when you can talk about it and feel understood. I admit that it&rsquo;s not easy to find your soul mate. Most people just don&rsquo;t care so deeply. I feel grateful that I found my significant other, but you can actually rediscover deep connections in people you already know. Don&rsquo;t assume that they don&rsquo;t want it, just because it wasn&rsquo;t like this before! When you start opening up, you might be surprised what you get back. I certainly reaped rewards.</p>
<p>One reason that deterred me from sharing was that raw thoughts and feelings are not stable. They might change tomorrow and what I said yesterday would feel like a lie.
So I only used to share results and facts. This is a good thing with more distant acquaintances. You don&rsquo;t want to confuse them with your wild mind. But with good friends and loved ones, it is so rewarding to think out loud. First, you get to understand each other much better. Second, you have much more interesting conversations and third you might discover something new. You get to learn different perspectives and can make better decisions!</p>
<p>Lately, I had been thinking about moving out from home again. Normally, I would only share the news with my family when I already made the decision and probably already found a flat. This time however, I shared the idea early with my aunt and it turns out that she is super supportive and actually knew of an awesome flat that will become available soon. Serendipity at it&rsquo;s best! Soon, I&rsquo;ll be moving in - thanks to thinking out loud.</p>
<p>It’s natural for thoughts and feelings to change. Sharing what we think in the moment is actually very honest, the exact opposite of what I believed. It’s honest to acknowledge that our thoughts are not always clear-cut and logical. Not every word needs to be taken literally. You are talking to a friend, not an interrogator. Over time we gain more information and more perspective, so it’s healthy to associate change with improvement instead of constantly fearing that we act inconsistently and worrying that we think differently tomorrow. It feels great to not be alone on this endless thought journey and it immensely enriches both experiences and learnings. As I’m writing this, I’m just thinking out loud. It needn’t be perfect, it’s just me.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>