<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Second-Brain - Category - Elcheads Site</title><link>http://elchead.me/categories/second-brain/</link><description>Second-Brain - Category - Elcheads Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://elchead.me/categories/second-brain/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Content collection - The power of Check-Later apps</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-12-06-content-collection/</guid><description><![CDATA[<!-- TODO add img -->
<p>How do you consume media? - It sounds like a silly question, but I think it&rsquo;s very much worth thinking about it. After all, we spend a considerable amount of time doing it. It might be to research something specific, to learn something new, or simply to entertain ourselves. The internet provides a rich resource of information, but it&rsquo;s probably also the most distracting source.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Notion - A powerful documenting tool for Notes, Projects, Wiki...</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/notion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/notion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I feel excited to share the tool that has most influenced my exploration of a more organized me. Many people see it as an alternative to Evernote, but for me, it felt much more powerful than a note-taking app. I immediately fell in love with its simplistic markdown approach, which easily yields attractive pages. I always had difficulties keeping notes that I would like to check again, which discouraged me from using them extensively. Notion completely changed my attitude toward note-taking and writing because it made it fun - Yes, it indirectly made me write this blog!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Second Brain - My life-changing companion</title><link>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-15-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://elchead.me/posts/2020-11-15-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the beginning of a bigger series on which I want to introduce some ideas about my new life companion. For me, this concept was pivotal in how I want to live. It helped me become clearer on what I want and focus on my priorities. I use it to offload information to have more capacities for being present-focused. Finally, I became fully digital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I struggled quite a bit on finding a proper word because it touches so many aspects. It is related to productivity, self-improvement, and knowledge management. In the end, I think that the term second brain, made famous by Tiago Forte, is maybe a good superordinate for what it tries to achieve. In fact, I was hugely inspired by him and adopted a lot of his ideas. He describes the second-brain as a knowledge management system. Once I got into this area, I discovered a lot of other content related to productivity and self-improvement. I took what seems useful to me, and I am still exploring.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>