<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Adrian's Site</title><link>https://astobbe.me/</link><description>Adrian's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astobbe.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2022 - Goals</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/2022/</guid><description><![CDATA[<style>
  #callout {
    background: #22272e;
     

    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
      padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
</style>

<div id="callout">
  <div></div>
  <div id="callout-inner">TLDR, the short version is at the end :) </div>
</div>

<p>I hope you had a good start in the new year! I&rsquo;m late in the game, but I want to share my yearly goals for this year with you.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>My fuckups of 2021</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/fuckups-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/fuckups-2021/</guid><description>The only real mistake is the one from which we learn nothing - Henry Ford.
In 2021, I took more time to reflect on my failures. While doing my yearly review, I decided to pick 3 fuckups and share them with you. Maybe it can help you, avoid similar mistakes. And if not, may my naiveness at least make you laugh!
The MacBook that proved light as air Earlier this year, I bought a used MacBook Air.</description></item><item><title>Testable code has few mocks</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/js-testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/js-testing/</guid><description>Testing can sometimes seem hard and tedious. We might be faced with complex setup logic and many mocks. But this is a smell of poor code design. When properly done, mocks are rarely needed. TDD helps to avoid tight coupling and it naturally tends towards functional code. In this post, I cover how the functional style leads to less error prone code and fewer code to be tested. Moreover, we will explore when it is proper to use mocks.</description></item><item><title>Tools and shortcuts for MacOS</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/tools-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/tools-mac/</guid><description>After many years of Windows, I switched to MacOS this year - with no regrets. Besides the big plus of being UNIX-based, I got to appreciate the user-friendliness and smooth integrations with the iPad. My favourites are using the iPad as an external sreen, Airdrop, signing documents and continuity.
But the system switch, also made me find new ways to interact with it. In the following I want to show a few tools and shortcuts that optimize my workflow on the Mac:</description></item><item><title>Building a Journaling habit with Obsidian</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/building-a-journaling-habit-with-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/building-a-journaling-habit-with-obsidian/</guid><description>Journaling is one of the habits that many find desirable, yet few achieve to establish. I felt the same struggle, until I found a nice workflow in my notetaking app Obsidian that I want to share with you.
The value of Journaling I believe that people fail to journal regularly because it&amp;rsquo;s never urgent. So it recedes from the urgent but not necessarily important tasks. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s those that would probably most benefit from it.</description></item><item><title>Unix cheatsheet - Beyond the basics</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/unix-cheatsheet/</guid><description>We developers use the terminal a lot and there are a lot of tricks that can ease our work. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking beyond the essentials of getting stuff done in the shell! The quickest way to find what you need is probably to use tldr. But the frequently used hacks are best learned once to know about all the good stuff and work effectively. I recently found the great The Linux Command Handbook from Freecodecamp and went over it to extract the useful bites that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Fixing CSV parsing - First attribute not regonized (BOM)</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/csv-parse/</guid><description>Today, I wanted to read a CSV file from Notion and stumbled on the issue that my first attribute was not properly read. I validated my code on a another file before, but on this file it just didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Turns out that I had the same issue with another npm library. What bothered me was that when printing the object, I could see the attribute, but it had single quotes around it and was printed in green.</description></item><item><title>Mental Models - How they contribute to a happy life</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/mental-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/mental-models/</guid><description>Mental models are how we see and interpret the world. In reality, nothing has meaning, the world is just full of events obeying the laws of the universe. These laws constrain how we live: time is finite and irreversible, gravity puts us on the ground, physical needs ensure survial, etc. But beyond that everything is really up to our minds. We are all born within this frame, but over time we all have different experiences.</description></item><item><title>CKAD preparation - Tips for the Kubernetes exam</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/ckad/</guid><description>Recently, I took the Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exam and would like to share some tips for the preparation. Be aware that at the end of September, an updated 2021 version will be released, so contents will change a bit. Nevertheless, the exam contains 20 questions that need to be completed in 2 hours. So its crucial to be quick and comfortable with the kubectl CLI and formatting yaml files. But first things first:</description></item><item><title>Smart file organization - How PARA works for me after 8 months</title><link>https://astobbe.me/posts/para/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://astobbe.me/posts/para/</guid><description>More than half a year ago, I started building my second brain - an intent to store information digitally to offload it from your brain. Organization and structure are crucial for this system to work, even more than content collection. I can tell from past experience of dead archives that I had long forgotten about their existence. But even worse, file corpses can make it harder to find what we want.</description></item></channel></rss>